what's up dorks it's me Raymundo from
rocket power I'm happy y'all are here I
appreciate anybody who is interacting
um listening taking any time out of your
day to listen to anything that I make or
create or do or um any of it like it's
very cool so very much appreciate you if
you could if you don't mind like follow
subscribe just whatever app you're on
right now just like hit whatever it is
whatever the little
heart or the like or the whatever if you
have time to leave a review do that but
otherwise just live your life you know
do your thing I don't like lean reviews
myself so I appreciate anybody who
interacts with it uh this episode is
fantastic of course with the wonderful
Spencer Hicks the uh the best of the
best reoccurring guests I always enjoy
our conversations very philosophical
often on the same page of kind of like
symbolism and and meaning
um so yeah it's a great episode lots of
dope stuff that happens in the last half
if you don't want to listen a whole two
and a half hour whatever it is episode
just split it up listen to some today
and some tomorrow so the next day
whatever you got
um lots of episodes incoming
um I'm still you know trying to work out
life work schedule and and maintaining
um trying to have like a good product
here and make it sound decent and you
know make the thumbnails and make the
clips and all that sort of stuff so
uh I'm keeping it going keeping it
rocking thanks again I appreciate
everybody for listening check me out um
on Instagram it's where I'm most active
Jacob from the internet and uh follow
interact with any of it thank you guys
so much be well drink some water stretch
stretch before you run stretch after you
run
don't forget to move your body around go
outside in the morning it's good for you
live your life smile peace out let go of
the tension in your shoulders read from
your diaphragm you know you know all the
tags take care of yourself love yourself
let's get into the episode knowledge is
power
[Music]
what are you what have you been into man
I haven't talked to you in a while I
know it's been a while it's funny every
time we start texting it ends up not
being because each of our replies is
always so elaborate and long
like it's too hard every time we're like
oh we have so much to catch up on that's
why we need like a weekly catch-up
session just to like fill each other in
it's hard because it's like those little
bouts of inspiration come
semi-fleetingly as well there's like two
to three hours of the day where I'm like
really jazzed enough to send a seven
page text message and then also read one
and respond to it yep so I'll feel like
I'll be on one send you something and
I'm like there's no way that you can
reciprocate this at this moment and I'm
totally fine with that and then that
will happen you'll send me a text two
days later it'll be like all right I'll
read it whenever I can comprehend this
well that's pretty much how it is and
when it's not so much like hey how you
been oh not much just been working like
usually when we bring up something that
we want to discuss this one with one
another it's like it's inherently
philosophical it's it's heavy yeah I
also can't explain it through text all
the way either like it's just not a
means of communication that lends to a
like really concise elaboration so not
only is it be hard to understand anyways
it's really hard to understand through a
really disjointed honestly sub-optimal
communication method yeah it's it's
that's exactly right it's it's literally
already something that is near
impossible to put into words words
already kind of dilute the whole thing
as it is but when you're trying to text
it it's even worse it's like having a
serious conversation for Via Twitter or
something
that's not
so if I uh if I'm looking down at all I
brought like just some notes for this
because I feel like I there's like a lot
of stuff I've been into after I got out
of school I've just had the room to have
my own intellectual Pursuits so I just
wrote some stuff down so I'll forget
about it if I don't I would love to
um I would love to have you lead the
conversation so to say in that way like
wherever we go if you want to uh choose
the next chapter that we turn a page
into Feel Free at any time to change the
subject to bring up what you've written
down because I have I mean I I always
glance at like what we've been texting
about the last few weeks or whatever
um but I don't have anything written
down I'm just kind of here today
so
yeah I actually do want to ask you about
you said you went to a a philosophy
meditation combo yeah yeah I do want to
hear about yeah so pretty exciting I
went two nights ago
and so so it's it's through that app um
I feel like my vocal is so it's it's
through that app uh
in a sec I think I might just up a
little bit too high
so it's the app Meetup like meetup.com
and so I've I've like when I first moved
to Austin a year ago I signed up and you
do all your interests and it shows you
like I get emails every day saying hey
there's a yoga class or there's a
philosophy class or we're going to talk
about this or we're um we're gonna do
this book club whatever it is and I just
have not gone I finally went to my first
one and I just decided I got one of the
emails and it was uh yoga philosophy
meditation and the subject was Free Will
versus Destiny and like well that's at
my wheelhouse is something I'm
contemplating quite often I just decided
to go
um it was wonderful man so uh it's a
meditation center it was just like a one
of the units of a building like on the
outside I'm like okay it's kind of like
an office looking building and you walk
inside and it's basically like a warm
inviting home
um and you know there's pictures of you
know like enlightened leaders all over
the all over the wall
um
very welcoming there's like chairs
around
um a main area where someone would sit
in the uh leader like I don't know what
what to call him like I don't know if
he's like the teacher or like if he
prefers some sort of guru-esque title it
doesn't seem like he does
but uh yeah he led it so we did we did
some chanting
um
you know as a way to like Center he kind
of explained what what the mantras were
and how they helped us to kind of like
get into our own body and connect to God
blah blah blah
um and then we went through basically a
lecture where he did where he discussed
uh Free Will versus Destiny it was very
it was tasty I really liked it a lot it
was it was nice
um and then he was it was very open to
discussion at the end
and it was what was his Free Will
conclusion I'm very curious to hear this
because and also to clarify I'm pretty
sure it gets got into like a Rousseau
incense
right or like a spinosian sense where
it's not like the capital G God it's
like God is everything like yeah yeah
um yeah very yeah Buddhist Buddhist you
know maybe even Hindu understanding
um
it's essentially that
God it's so hard to even think of like
exactly what he said just because I put
so much of my own [__] into it as he was
talking
um
I mean it's that we that we do have
I don't even know if I could summarize
his overall points on it I mean
basically that we do have free will but
um I think it's kind of always in the
caveat of it's
it's within a box like we
you know I can't even recall I feel like
I'm gonna completely butcher I I was
thinking about going again tonight if I
have time because he does it like a
couple times a week but um maybe I'll
get a refresher and text you about it I
can't even I can't even pinpoint exactly
what his points were on Free Will yeah
for a while I was like kind of a hard
determinist or a couple things couple
reasons mostly biological reasons like
your series of neural synapses that um
people can predict what you're going to
do before it happens and
because you technically didn't choose to
be born and you didn't choose your
nature any of your genetics or your
nurture or the environment you're
exposed to everything is just like a
cascading series of events that you
technically never chose it's just a
response to the last one I think that's
wrong
I think that's wrong recently I uh I've
been listening to a couple thinkers and
um
one of them talked about the
neurological studies where they can
predict what you're going to do before
you do it immediately
and yeah that posits the fact that we
can measure that neural response but it
fails to consider one the material
aspect that we exhibited enough will to
even learn that in the first place
one like on a material sense and then
two the power to deliberate and say no
it's like saying yes and having an
Impulse to something is definitely not
your choice but like saying no kind of
is
so
I uh I'm bouncing back and forth on it
yeah my my view is constantly expanding
I've been um
something that I'm always thinking about
and trying to like wrap my head around
and like some days I feel like I believe
it some days I've um
I don't want to use the word believe
some days I embody it uh and I feel what
it feels like to to feel it
um and in a lot of it even the um the
meditation teacher whatever I don't know
what to call it
um he has one of those long complicated
names too that like you you get when you
go to the you know Tibetan mountains and
you're like Ramana
like I don't know
um I probably sound so arrogant but uh
the the concept of of Karma and past
lives comes into it and I know that on
the surface that sounds like oh boy like
you know Soul reincarnation and all that
but there is like so I have heard people
explain it in ways where it completely
does kind of like answer certain
problems you know if you think ramdas
says um
uh I think his teacher told him you know
your lifetime uh it's like like an
understanding of infinity it's uh if a a
dove with a silk scarf in its mouth is
to pass over the mountain in the time
that it would take for that silk scarf
rubbing again or pass over the mountain
once every 100 years the time it would
take for that silk scarf to rub away
that mountain is like how long an
Infinity is that's how long you're alive
for that's how long like your soul
reincarnates for so this is just a
lifetime within our reincarnations and
so to look at free will in the sense of
like I am I am Jake with free will in
these you know 100 years whatever 80
years whatever it is
um it's not necessarily so much free you
have the free will to
um
choose to
I don't know like be in alignment with
God or not in alignment with God I don't
know it gets complicated
they're all very metaphysical
abstract it's actually really funny
though so I've been um reading at a very
notoriously hard thinker his name's High
Digger he's German he
was a materialist and a phenomenological
phenomenologist from I believe he's
alive maybe 100 years ago but like a lot
of his thoughts presupposed
a lot of the thinking that has come in
like modernity and he wrote a book
called I believe time and being
and it kind of it's funny because it
lines up with a lot of Eastern ideas
kind of incidentally which is
he retorts that
the traditional logic of the I think
therefore I am like that's how we arrive
at we are a being because we can think
like that is like uh evidence of being
alive or being a conscious actor
um
takes one thing for granted and that's
just like being in general like you have
to exist first to then have that
Consciousness thing occur and all of
that occurs in like a temporality so
your Consciousness is like unbridledly
connected to uh to time itself so it's
kind of got the same temporal feeling to
it it's just very interesting to see
through lines through very disparate
thinkers and ideas right yeah no I love
it I really like when um like a newer
science comes about and it's like oh
it's presented in this way and it's like
nice and organized and then it's like oh
yeah they're like it there's actually
pretty much the same thing in the
bhagavad-gita you know or or some other
like Rich text you know it all kind of
comes full circle and it is
um the the the time thing is pretty
profound you know we are kind of locked
in our perception of time and it's
interesting to think about if you think
about like time travel
um we think of time travel like kind of
like
immaturely sometimes like like um
it's a misunder our understanding of
like the Back to the Future sort of time
travel where you go back like that is a
vast like misunderstanding of what we
are and like what reality really is and
how we fit into it you know not just our
ego Persona either just our actual
experience of right now
yeah the difference between like time
itself as like a structural concept and
time as you perceive it that's anchored
in Concepts and weird temporalities like
you anchor your your sense of time and
existence through like events objects
symbols cultural events stuff like that
so it's not like it doesn't feel linear
so the way we experience time is just
like not time as it is and it can be
really really really distorted and uh
actually Heidegger talks about that too
so when he does the example for why the
I think therefore I am thing is not
necessarily like the initial question to
ask
he talks about so like if a worker has a
hammer you because you're steeped in the
hammer like you you have it in your hand
and you're using it just kind of becomes
a big part of you like you take it for
granted when it breaks you're really
super immediately aware that it's broken
and like all of a sudden you notice
everything so it's kind of like that
that temporality is being broken
and I thought that was interesting just
because
it kind of transfers to just taking a
step back out of like all the stuff that
shoots you through life
where you kind of stop paying attention
to anything you kind of get burdened to
the mundane and you actually it does
feel like time travel right it'll be
Friday all of a sudden you're like oh
[__] hmm yeah our ability to like adapt
to something like not only just a tool
be an extension of our hand but you know
even if like even our technology is kind
of an extension of our hand like it's a
you know a psychological tool in a lot
of Senses but it allows our our our hand
and our like sense of our being to be
expanded just like yeah it goes on
notice and it's even transferable to
like ideology as well like it's
something that you're just steeped in
all the time you're never looking at it
uh we're told that we live in a society
that's post ideology but it is just
something that is ever present no you
just stop looking at it you just forget
that it's happening and until it kind of
breaks you got to look at your own or
something really bad happens you don't
really look at it
like oh [__] I've been taking all this
for granted and all the things that I
thought were implicit truths are
actually subjective and taught to me
well I think it speaks to our ability to
uh like just get used to things like we
could just we could get used to any
state or like I was I was actually
reading um I went on a walk this morning
and was re-listening to Viktor frankl's
man search of meaning
and uh it was getting to the part where
um
gosh what was it he's kind of like he's
talking about different ways they were
finding joy and like it was almost like
a currency for someone to like perform
some sort of art or sing like amongst
the amongst the prisoners you know
because that like it's like oh I haven't
felt joy for for two months like I just
remember oh yeah oh God and then they
they talk about this part where someone
came running into the chambers or
running into the um you know prison uh
their their bunks or whatever he was
like come come look outside and they
look outside and there was like a
beautiful sunrise or a beautiful sunset
or something and uh and they were able
to like in the midst of all that like
see see the beauty you know and so it's
just interesting you know to even for
the human mind to find beauty amongst
all of that suffering you know in in the
concentration camps in Auschwitz and
stuff so but yeah we we just get used to
it in a sense and we only notice you
know I guess when it's broken it's like
when the state is changed that's when we
notice yeah I mean that's like hi to
your whole point and actually he calls
those little moments when the thing
breaks or temporal ecstasies
like you finally like oh something has
been shattered it's a like some it has
become immediately obvious and relevant
that something has been here the whole
time and I've just been not perceiving
it because I've been steeped in it
seems like we're kind of going through
culturally civilization-wide like we're
going through a ton of those like um
I I hate to bring in this word right
here but Awakenings
um they're kind of like our Awakenings
in a sense right like you you understand
something
suddenly to where you can step outside
of it like oh I didn't realize I was
doing that or like oh I didn't realize
like I was holding this tool it was just
a piece of me
Maybe
maybe we'll see so another uh so the the
paper that I wrote uh was uh like
um
it was on ghost in the show which is a
anime sci-fi cyberpunk film from the mid
90s and it's
asks a bunch of questions like what is
life like it's ontological movie so it's
trying to determine like uh what is the
nature of existence like do robots live
like what is it really and that's not
really the nature that I analyzed it in
because it's like contained film but I
actually analyzed it
juxtaposed to its remake which strips
all of the meaning out of that and makes
it just kind of like a generic sci-fi
film and the lens that I used to analyze
it through is a man named Mark Fishers
and his writings are a criticism of
neoliberalism so which it can be
categorized as like Ronald Reagan
Margaret Thatcher X politics where we
took away all social programs and like
anything that would help people in
society just for like Market pressure
which led to Media being recycled So
like
um instead of artists having the freedom
in society to make new art they would
just repackage old art to sell it again
that's why you see a lot of sequels now
there's like 40 million Marvel movies
like nothing really new ever comes out
it's kind of like
the same thing is just remixed over and
over again
and uh he posits that
like the future is dying essentially
like it's the slow cancellation of the
future and we never really experience
anything new so I used that idea to
analyze the next movie
where
oh what is it
or I mean it basically just is a worse
version or like a simulacrum
of the first one so are you saying the
remake
devoid of like the the themes and just
kind of like recycled Nostalgia like
ruins the point of of the movie like
like what what really did your what did
your paper say like what was the yeah
I'm struggling to figure out where I
want to start this because this so his
work is complex but it's built on
another person's work that's complex so
maybe I should start with that one so uh
his work is inspired by a French
philosor named John boliard and he came
up with the idea of the of hyper reality
and uh he wrote a book that I'm
currently that's what I'm reading is uh
similar lacrum and simulation it's
actually what the Matrix is about it's
in the opening scene that book that Neo
looks at which in the context of that
film it means something way different if
you are aware of that versus not
but so he talks about like his system is
uh on semiotics and symbols so the study
of how words and symbols mean something
are used in society which is actually
like a lot of what my education was
turns out I found out posthumously
so he posits that we went from like a
normal agricultural culture where we
just like made Regular goods for a
really long time and then we traded them
everything the reality was as it was
there was nothing distorting it in any
way
we shifted into a production stage where
people stopped having that Liberation at
work
and um marketing kind of became a thing
at that point in time because it's like
uh we have like a Mercantile capitalism
you're making money
you're buying things you need to be sold
through images and persuasion
to now we have like an Information
Society so it's like post-cultural or I
mean you could classify it as postmodern
where
every symbol that we see is no longer
really rooted in something that is real
it's just like a copy or a simulacrum of
a previous symbol
so everything is self-referential that's
what the use of logos are you can see it
in like interior design like all of the
minutas it's all everything in the way a
house is laid out is supposed to
communicate to you something like an old
Victorian house it was like really
traditionally cluttered there was like
paintings everywhere and this is
supposed to communicate to you that
there's like wealth and Prestige here
and that is slowly morphed into now
we've got like Supreme shirts right like
this is like a weird symbol of wealth
and uh all of the ads that we see
everything is just kind of like
self-referential in a way you can see it
my favorite example is like the Travis
Scott McDonald's
merger so there is like fundamentally
nothing really real about this like
Travis Scott his only image is just hype
you don't really know anything about him
and it's just this weird Mash of like
High symbolism but there's it's very
vapid right there's no way to make sense
of any of it it's just like the whole
thing has become self-referential
and Mark Fisher talks about that and
that's why I talked about this film
because in devoid of any real true
meaning in any of these symbols because
they're all hyper real uh we are doomed
to just repeat
the ones that we've already seen because
it seems like we've lost the ability to
make anything new which would be the
second ghost in the show hmm yeah I mean
that's that is this weird thing where
why aren't we creating new things why
are we recycling why why are we trying
to grasp at things that like like once
we kind of realize the illusory nature
of things why aren't we able to go like
oh and then you know take the take the
mask off our face or take the glasses
off our face and and readjust or is that
kind of like what what we are
approaching in society is like a
re-understanding of symbols and meanings
instead of recycling old ones and trying
to make them work well there's just like
no
real symbols or meanings anymore they're
just all self-referential like we
stopped to perceive a reality like this
is really through the nature of
Technology too just like the way we are
engaging with images and symbols now is
uh so different than it once was in this
kind of really distorts reality in a lot
of ways and a big part of this is Market
fundamentalism so
people that are making images that are
persuasive movies art needs to be able
to sell it in the best way to sell that
is to make images that are
self-referential and nostalgic
so it is completely handicapped and
hamstrung the ability for the artist to
make new art and you can see I mean it
is one of the most destructive things
physically imaginable for you to
hamstring art and culture it's like a
really important structure that needs to
happen it needs to be able to challenge
things and it really hasn't been able to
and Mark Fisher's whole work is he was
like really into the underground Punk
scene in England so he talks about a lot
of the artists that have come out of
these neoliberal periods just being
really disenfranchised and then
after about 10 years in the late 90s it
just stopped happening we're just
getting repriced pop music the repraisal
of like Lo-Fi beats is a really good
microcosm example of this so it's just
like a really comforting noise with a
bunch of sound bites from your childhood
that's it so it's just like
because we yearn for something new in
something that feels good because stuff
is so bad all right like the market
fundamentalism has been terrible for
everybody our generation is like
destitute houses are half a million
dollars you just need something that is
comforting and you it's the only place
we can find it
so what is it
so what were the correlations that you
drew what was like the main things that
you drew from the original
to the new remake like like what did you
pose was lost
I think that I should talk about why I
chose to do it anyways because I really
forced it in a lot of ways it turned out
pretty good this is like a 26 page paper
so
it's like it's gonna be kind of hard to
condense this and honestly I would
probably need more notes than I
currently have to do it really concisely
but uh it was mostly fun word play
that's why I got it started so
it started out with
a thinker named Jacques derida who came
up with an idea called hauntology which
is a just a just a devilishly clever
plan words because
in French
the word for ontology which is the
thought process in science and
philosophy of being in existence
which is hauntology which is focusing on
what is not there so it's like haunting
ontology and that the front part of that
word is actually silent in French so
they are the same word but not when
they're written
so I'm like that is devilishly smart
Wicked intelligent so and it's uh used
to critique retro futurism
normally which is like okay well Ghost
in the Shell is a cyberpunk film and uh
what haunts things ghosts do
this is a ghost in the show is a movie
about ontology other than being and
knowing but it just happens that the
second film is a hauntological example
yeah of the first one because it's just
like a it's a simulacrum it's a hyper
real
adaptation that is just like a mimic
copy of the first one and because we
can't get new art
we are haunted by old art
damn
yeah so that's so like like metal and so
you know our at its core but
it also like too too real I guess it's
metal because it's too real yeah so uh I
that's that's why I started it and I
actually just over the course of
researching just like I have never
fallen in love with a thinker more than
Mark Fisher he just speaks so collically
he was alive really recently he actually
committed suicide sadly in 2017. but it
just I've never encountered somebody
that is a verbalized how I feel
like I'd say so potently so nicely and
in a way that is like beautiful with
examples that I understand very cleanly
yeah yeah yeah I mean you sent me that
video I was like at the airport or
something you sent me that video I think
it was on hauntology and it was I was
like I re-listened to it when I got back
onto the airplane too because it was
just like oh my God I wanted to write
down everything he was saying because
like that's what I'm trying to put into
words when I'm talking to people
sometimes so yeah I'm totally yeah I
really it it's made me think of you a
lot because in a way I felt like you are
encumbered by the situation of society
when it comes to the fact that uh art is
so hamstrung like culturally and the
symbols that we use are just so they're
just so reused and re-washed and the uh
Ecology of Art
is just being destroyed by the fact that
uh money needs to happen and the market
doesn't accept people that are uh into
abstracts and offshoots in uh novelty
we've just lost the ability to do that
just because it doesn't make money it's
not Market appealing that's why we get
Avengers 12 instead of yeah new
superhero right yeah which is like like
you're missing the point of art you're
actually like you're draining the source
of of what the art is supposed to be you
know like put pushing against the edge
of what human beings have ever known or
done or thought about is is what an
artist does what do you think you
actually had started to say something a
few minutes ago about
um about like the role of the artist do
you have an opinion uh on let's say not
to put words in your mouth but like the
importance of the artist in a society or
like the importance of the you know
poetic even comedic thinker I am you can
you can remove some importance that's
that's no I think that art in itself
music in particular uh poetry uh thought
I guess in general
uh is
really important for society to be
pressing up against the edges of it and
most especially there to fight hegemonic
belief systems that's what art has been
for like it just is there to criticize
how things are and how the power
structures are so if that is usurped by
the power structures
which is global Capital neoliberal
Market fundamentalism if they control
that art and they kind of drip feed it
in we get nothing that is ever new and
nothing that ever questions that and it
leads to like just such a potent
existential dread where you just feel
like
it's just everything is so watered down
and the same and there's just like
nothing revolutionary about it when art
from the 80s
like the Wall came out like stuff was
like really adamantly pressing against
all the systems that uh technically bind
us but that is no longer occurring and
the place of Art in society is to do
that and if it cannot do that uh people
get very mad and they should be mad I
mean I'm mad about it it's terrible
we're ruthlessly boring too
so boring
100 it really is I'm with you a million
percent on that where is the
where is you know the the
Clash of London now like where is where
are the punk rock people in a society
now like the people who were like
um you know pointing out because it's
almost like we've like they've been
creepily integrated into society and
sold back to us and it's almost like a
fake version of wearing wearing the
leather jacket you know what I mean like
it's a that there's like a faux version
of
pistols you know just like it was a joke
all along
yeah so this is
I um a lot of my thought process
analysis comes as a critique to Capital
and it's not and it's technically a
Marxist criticism but it's not because
it's just capitalism bad it's because
capitalism is like a hegemonic structure
it's literally just like the status quo
that's what it's symbol of so if I'm if
I'm going to refer to it as that it's
more of how that affects the ideology of
societies I'm preempting an argument
it's how it affects the ideology and
thought process and production of
society more than like the basic
economics of it the whole communication
and ritualistic pathway in which that we
derive at uh culture essentially so
capitalism eats everything it just it
just does so like you get any
revolutionary thinker you can see this
in um
uh in gay movements uh any feminist
movements uh the
the Civil Rights Movement so this is
something that is inherently really
radical and important right it is by
nature completely going against what
capital is it's questioning the
hegemonic structures and the power
structures that are currently
in place
Capital will defang it
make remove it of all revolutionary
context package it cleanly and then sell
it back to you
and it just does that it eats everything
and then people just get comfortable in
that and especially so if you're a fat
artist you're the artist okay let's say
you have a very revolutionary thoughts
um you get pushed through the music
industry you make a lot of money
well the system that you were once
criticizing now works for you really
well
so you're in the three percent of people
that really have a vested interest in it
not being criticized actually so it
Waters down the Revolutionary art and
this is not like an explicit Behavior
right nobody is actively like hey we
gotta recruit
X rapper and then make them like work
for McDonald's it's just like a thing
that happens because of the cultural
incentives in society I think a lot of
times we think it's like evil
billionaire billionaires are making this
happen and I think it's more what you're
saying is it's it's a result of what
capitalism is it's yeah which is still
bad and I actually billionaire is not
off the hook but I don't think that they
on purpose do it it's just a consequence
and it's it's bad no matter what you
know I just don't think that there's
like some like Goblin somewhere pulling
a lever telling like the White Stripes
to be something else or whatever
whispering in Jack White's ear telling
him what to say on the record it's just
and I think that that's the Insidious
nature of it is it's just the way that
the incentive structure of society is
Will inherently defang everything it
just eats everything it's honestly
impressive
that something could be so potently
hegemonic with it's so technically
really unstable every 10 years it just
almost fails like the whole all of the
economic sphere almost just like fails
all the time it's like one of the least
stable systems you could probably ever
make and yet it's somehow never actually
fails all the way and also eats
everything that ever contends with it
that's insane that's crazy
just keep going
yeah I mean what what
at what level do we as a species like
like snap out of it though like like
quit putting paint over it you know quit
quit rearranging the deck chairs on the
Titanic so to say
yeah create a structure somehow that
do you do you think that a lot of our
this might be a huge side step so we can
ignore but do you think that a lot of
our um investment into like Ai and
technology is like like some sort of
answer to the fear like hopefully if we
just create this it'll answer all the
questions like if we you know lean
towards some sort of Singularity
movement it will help us all out and
then if we could take all this data that
we have that we don't know how to deal
with and how to you know make a workable
system for the future of humanity and
hopefully these robots will help us out
do you think it's anything like that
um actually bulliard talks about this
he's in semi-critical of the systems in
place because of
technology I can't remember the example
of this these are all really complex
thoughts that I didn't create and I
don't really know enough about to fully
elaborate but I'm gonna try
so the way that systems work now in
general their informational systems that
operate independently of each other that
act as filters based on a like at
abstract number so like the school
systems grades uh the banking system is
credit
um anything else that the medical system
is your medical history
you kind of just get like ping-ponged
around this system and it's like really
strong and nobody's technically
controlling it because it's computerized
so that leads to really interesting
systems of control that are technically
not
singular but they are hegemonic as in
they all act as filters for any action
that would operate outside of that and
that's directly due to the mechanistic
actions of society that were not present
before that makes sense it's like if you
live in a village like that that's not
how you got filtered through Society
but now you get filtered through Society
in like 15 different ways with all
different numbers
so be it's it's just so ever present
like in and it feels almost like a frog
boiling of water because when we had
Kings or tyrants you knew you knew you
were being controlled there was no
illusion of freedom in any way it's like
yeah I'm a certified make rice that's it
so I can live here
but now you feel like you have choice
because you're being you kind of have a
little bit of freedom in all of these
systems that are playing and nobody's
technically controlling them
and you can like choose your health care
I guess which is like a false illusion
but there's like a there's a facade of
choice so people don't feel not free
they don't feel controlled and they
don't feel like that there's a hegemonic
structure that is disallowing them from
Breaking Free but almost all of the
informational systems that we engage
with and just do that
yeah it's like we're suffering but we
have the illusion of of somehow being in
control like it's like our we're
distracted from our suffering we're
we're suffering and we're in a prison
cell but we got a Game Boy you know
yeah absolutely
I mean it's just uh
this is the systems of control they're
really Insidious and they're really hard
to see if you're not looking at it it's
like you got the hammer and it works
right hasn't broken yet technically I
know that's not a one-to-one example but
it's the same uh recognition of that
is there is everything that we like
think is necessarily true or that is
like um
implicit in society all of these systems
like it's just how it is but because you
didn't look at it all the way like all
of these systems are communicating
something to you they're all technically
signs and symbols and that communication
is objection control
but because you feel free within them
because we are told we are free with
them them you um you take them as
implicit and you don't look at it the
hammer is working it's not broken yet
how many like
towards the ends at the end you know as
far as if we look at our history towards
the end of other civilizations
it seemed like they would likely come up
with similar observations that we have
been like that that modern thing I mean
that guy died in 2017. is it Mark Fisher
that you were talking about yeah I mean
that was that was bulliards thought
process on machines but no it's inspired
it's basically the same like thought
line chain how do we how do we like
within with real intelligence
take where we're at and our observations
of them and um
and not are like like mine and your
self-importance situation but just
well like like how do how do we take
like hey here here's the thing that's
going on and how do we actually like
actualize it how do we you know because
because after a while if we start to
understand oh we're doing the thing that
other civilizations did right before
they they ended like they were able to
assess kind of their situation
um and come to these similar conclusions
we find ourselves to those same
Crossroads so this is a good you know uh
understanding of our future and where
we're going to go like how how would a
civilization
a just course I think that would be all
it's so close modernity can literally
not be compared to any other time in
history because of that semiolacrum
simulation hyper real setting right so
because like reality was apparent and
obvious in other cultures it was more
easy to discern what is occurring even
if it was technically everybody is just
a part of their own specific ideology
and same thought process and truths
Universal in their small microcosm of
the world right it's a Greek city-state
there's like some basic contentions but
everybody is just like the reality is
what it is
because of the way that the media Works
in general which is like for better for
worse like it's just how it is
um you can be subjected to and believe a
large series of things and there's no
actual clean thought line or a belief
structure that is occurring and I'm not
saying that's good I prefer polysemic
societies where there can be many truths
we just appreciate all of them and then
we intersect them so here are all the
available readings of something we
conclude something new in the middle
right but
it is impossible to make sense of it
it's just like it cannot occur like
consensus is just not a mechanism that
can be reached anymore this is not going
to happen because everybody is just like
steeped in ideology the hammer of
ideology is not broken nobody can see it
so it's just like we take all these
things that we see as implicit truths it
just it's Common Sense which is not a
thing that's real it's just something
that's reaffirming all the things that
you've been taught by hegemonic
structure
and uh it doesn't actually change it's
not going to I'm very nihilistic about
this exact thing unless people can uh
question see the hammer break
which is
you hear people complain about ideology
all the time like as a concept like some
thinkers do that you know that's why
it's because it's just like you're just
steeped in it like I'm it's like eating
out of a trash can all of the time and
you can't stop and that trash can is
ideology
delicious
it reminds me
[Music]
um
I mean I suppose so now that you've seen
you've seen the good place all the way
through right yeah I love the good
points yeah I think it's great yeah
there's a moment that I find myself in
often where I'm sitting on my hands
um the moment where you know towards the
end of the end of the show where they
have Phoebe from friends and forget the
actor's name
um but she's in like like the really
good place you know
do you remember uh her showing up
uh I don't know so I actually I don't
think I've seen it all the way through
necessarily because my girlfriend why we
watch stuff differently so she'll like
binge watch stuff we're in like a
sitting and I usually don't so I've seen
like 70 of it disparately okay so I
don't remember that too basically they
get to the to the end where it's you can
have everything you ever wanted forever
and it's unlimited Margaritas it's
unlimited Daiquiris and they're
literally the best tasting Daiquiris you
could ever have and it's complete bliss
all the time
um but uh and I think I've even
mentioned this to you before there's
there's a moment where she like breaks
out and she like remembers it's like all
these delicious Daiquiris but then she
remembers like oh uh yeah my brain has
completely turned to Mush like it's
nothing like like I'm I'm lost in the
illusion like she doesn't remember she
was some like a big mathematician and
she completely forgot like all of her
intelligence from before because her
brain just turned to Mush from from what
she was doing
um
and it kind of reminds it like sometimes
that's where I find where where I I find
myself and I'm sure many you know people
who think about these sort of things
find themselves is you almost snap out
of your like Bliss and enjoying
enjoying the dance of life to go like oh
wow this is like this is this isn't it
like we're kind of going towards the
edge of something here that's not
sustainable
so
and um it's definitely not sustainable
just the modes of a production that we
use in general I mean look like look at
the climate crisis stuff like that and
Marx had a concept that was uh it's the
base superstructure model so the base of
his Society is the means of production
in which that we make good Services how
the fundamental economics works and this
might be reductive and it might not
necessarily perfectly apply to
everything but it's just a simple model
so that this condition that people are
their material condition what they're
subjected to informs the superstructure
which is culture ideology philosophy
uh politics anything that would require
extrapolation from that and you're just
kind of steeped in that all the time
it's the it's the unbroken Hammer it's
the working Hammer right you just take
it as implicit it's just a truth it's
not it's a construct
and uh that is fundamentally
unsustainable the one that we have for
anybody and it's like pretty obvious
that it's self-terminating
so
so what we need is we need magical
thinking
we need
a real artist who isn't caught in the um
the capitalism version of being an
artist yeah I just uh
I don't think any artist really wants to
be necessarily
and it's interesting because you see the
pushback on revolutionary movements in
general like
people will hate feminism or just like
any any movement any social movement
that is in direct contradiction to that
there is like a pretty big media outcry
against it in a lot of ways
and then you will also see
even people who are sympathetic to it
will
commit nothing more than symbols and
gestures like hey we stand in solidarity
with X movement but you're a politician
you don't ever do anything about it
because you benefit from the hegemony
like the way that things are
the base that has been constructed you
are direct recipient of so yeah dude to
quiet you down give you symbolic
victories and then nothing material will
ever change and changing the material
conditions is how we change the
superstructure which is how we get
actual change it blows my mind how many
people don't see the symbolic Victory
thing that you just mentioned like the
um uh uh there's a place here in Austin
called it was called the Russian house
and it's like this like big place and
you go and you drink there and it's been
here forever and that's the name of it
and then when the Ukraine Russia thing
started happening they changed their
name to the house
they got rid of the word Russia Russian
house
and I'm like ironically that is also a
capitalizing something because that you
know what that does bring publicity now
they make more money so it's just
[__] everywhere it just eats
everything there's like just nothing
kind of like mindless people are you
trying to attract to your business
though like people with money anybody
that will spend money doesn't matter
doesn't matter how you come across
currency I don't think it's that smart
though like I don't think that there was
anybody like I don't think the owner of
that was like uh let's get some eyes on
us like I mean maybe unconsciously they
were like
virtue signaling that that you know that
is what's going to happen like let's
make sure that everybody knows that
we're the good guys but um I don't it's
so weird like I like and then when you
go to speak about it we get caught in
between they're like oh so you so you're
so you're with Russia it's like what I
wasn't even in that context so I'm like
multiple layers uh removed from that we
get caught up with um with like the
words or like the the subject of it's
kind of like the arguments of free
speech like peop people get more
obsessed with the um
you know like the content within what
you're talking about like oh well you
don't believe in trans rights it's like
well no maybe I just believe in like
this person's ability to speak about
them or whatever like the Dave Chappelle
situation
but we just
like like our variability not only to
like discuss the proper things but even
like see the the correct angle or the
correct like setting of the argument we
completely waste time on the [__] I
think that uh words and prose are
actually really important and
it's not only making the criticism it's
making a criticism that is good right so
yeah I think that uh
the Russian house changing their name to
the house
is like whatever they want to do right
that's fine you're gonna bring somebody
in technically I virtue signal is
overused because technically almost
everything you do is a signal of virtue
the clothes you wear it's all like
almost all human behavior is a signal to
other humans about some kind of virtue
it's not necessarily something that I
can uh
crocheted at in any way like if that's
that's how you want to communicate
that's fine but I do think it is
short-sighted because
there's been a weird thing with all the
Russian stuff especially with small
businesses that are technically like
Russian
it's like you business owner bar owner
did not actually start a war and yes
this might be just a like you're showing
solidarity which is like totally fine
you know I don't even think that's a bad
move no big deal I actually think that
that's kind of cool
but it seems like
it's a little weird
like just uh maybe you could like put a
Facebook post out but if if that's how
you actually want to communicate you're
in solidarity and you're not supporting
Russia maybe they just don't want to get
their bar vandalized which happened to a
lot of Russian places yeah there's a lot
of very real material reasons why the
kitchen
I guess it just seems like the wrong
just seems like the wrong area of focus
on it like it's or or like a minuscule
area of focus over a bigger deal
like moralization or just uh having
those
uh virtue signals like that especially
when it comes to social improvements is
in response to having object
powerlessness to actually change the
material condition so uh I genuinely
believe the moralization of most things
is a response to the fact that we don't
have any revolutionary Pathways as in
the only way that we can put up a fight
or put a front up against something that
is so oppressive to everybody which is
just the systems that currently are in
control
is to uh do that
because like I mean you can't really
it's it's so ever present how else are
you gonna rebel I guess it is like it's
a move we can make yeah like so like
yeah it feels like it feels like agency
to be able to do that
um so I don't even I'm not even gonna
criticize that I think that's
necessarily a good thing it's just um
it's just unspoken
I I don't think my criticism was I mean
I I guess I use the specific example so
it sounds specific at them but it wasn't
so much in the subject matter as it is
like uh an example of our broader
confusion of how to like react to things
and how uh yeah like you said where it's
a
it's a something we can do I guess yeah
I do selflessness and you feel a little
bit of something well I know that uh you
don't like heuristics
you don't like the oh you didn't say the
right you didn't say the right well you
didn't make the right Noise Okay so I
infer that you uh hold all opinions and
opposition to thing that I like right
which
yeah that kind of sucks and I'm really
not a big fan of being a moralist in
general but it would make sense why that
would happen because there's like let's
see trans rights so because of the way
of the internet
and um how potently people are against
that even in very uh seemingly rational
according to the popular belief or ideas
of culture are against that like the
sports thing is a touch point which
nobody actually it's it's for you forces
you to question trans issues on a
broader sense but gives you a logical
reason to want to do it so there's a lot
of people that are just putting up a
massive front against trans issues which
would cause people who are
Pro trans issues I guess is a very
clumsy way to say it to infer any time
that you have any detraction
from any point that's being made that
you like everybody else
that they see is having the inverse idea
which is
their identity is not valid they're not
valid as people and they shouldn't
receive rights which is what a lot of
people would implicitly believe
even if they aren't aware of that their
actions and words would say that so I
understand the moralistic response not
saying it's always appropriate but it
definitely makes a lot of sense in a
social frustration level
yeah yeah yeah right it's I I I I'm
constantly
um I think you said it right I'm just
like I'm confused at the
over obsession with like the actual
language or like you're you're clearly
standing up for this side if you don't
whatever like it's it's uh
yeah I just think we focus on the wrong
parts of it of an issue and we don't
like we kind of get sidetracked as as
like oh we're solving the thing and
we're really going at the issue here but
it's we're completely missing it yeah
it's it's hard from our angle right
where it's like these issues even though
I am in 100 support of all of them and I
wish more people to have more rides in
Liberty no matter what their Creed
ethnicity identification is uh I'm
inherently not part of these communities
so the way that people talk about them
and interact with them inherently
doesn't affect me in any way
so sometimes it's easy to feel like it's
being talked about in the wrong way or
it is something that uh seems
unreasonable but it's just because I
don't have any skin in the game and a
lot of people do as well so just because
that I would think that maybe some kind
of like
more realistic brow beating or
um these very hyper-specific language
that is used is uh Missing the point
it's just not always necessarily about
me I guess that situation and I'm not
saying we should cowtail to everybody
that ever has any idea ever but I do
like to temper that sometimes with like
it's easy for me to say you're getting
enough progress even though I wouldn't I
don't necessarily say that but it's easy
for people to say yeah we're making our
progress because that progress doesn't
affect my material conditions at all
right I like I'm a white dude
right I come from like a middle to upper
class family like I no matter what
happens I'm gonna be fine
really no matter what social pressure
occurs so I don't know bro I think white
dudes are on the out right now I don't I
think it's it's unpopped I don't know
dude these days
I'm just joking
I don't know but you should look at
Congress
you're like white dude's been in my
dude's been in for a while
but yeah I don't know man
it's all just a [__] mess to be
honest because uh symbols are
self-referential and nothing means
anything
pretty much and we're just living
through our symbolism so what have you
what have you found yourself I mean now
that you have completed your thesis and
you're on the other side of this
schooling thing what have you found
yourself contemplating lately like like
even even if the answer is not on a
larger philosophical level like where do
you find yourself even in your in your
body in your in your life like like
what's been so I immediately when it was
done because I've been in school for
like seven years in a very circuitous
route I kind of spent I really was I
didn't grow up very fast you know
so I spent the first couple years of
college just kind of like going to music
festivals and just existing in it and
then over time I slowly became very
interested in philosophy and then I
really got into academics and my last
two years of school I had one specific
Professor he was he's a doctorate in
semiotics and a doctorate and I'd maybe
like uh pedagogy which is just teaching
in general but I can't remember what it
is something else Linguistics Maybe
but we have almost identical worldviews
I found out and I talked to him a lot we
became actually pretty close
and um
I slowly over time realized that all of
my thoughts all the philosophies that I
enjoy and all the thinkers I like are
just in the realm of semiotics so just
signs and symbols
and it really didn't all hit me I didn't
really understand that until I almost
got done writing that paper and
remembered what his major was like What
He is Specializes
holy [__] like this is the thing this is
the thing that I like enjoy and it is
like really intriguing to me and I
incidentally
I just learned a lot about
when school was over I really felt
ideologically sad like I felt like a
morning of a community I felt the loss
of intellectual pursuit in the space in
which that occurs in because it is a
it's a beautiful
safe free space that is doesn't have
anything like going to class together
literal just hanging out in school it's
just the one place in life that it's not
about show me the money you know you can
talk about abstract stuff I just felt
like without that space I was going to
lose
lose the time and well the area to do
abstractions three of show me the money
and uh to some degree I feel like that
that is true but after I mourned that
and had some closure it's just kind of
weird verbiage I'm using but it really
really felt like that uh winter
graduation had that weird like liminal
space emptiness feeling uh it's been
really liberating actually it's now
I've realized that I still love
intellectual Pursuit and now I can just
do it as freely as I want whenever I
want that's pretty much all I've done
since I've been done it's just like read
and listen to stuff
so you don't feel uh because I was going
to jump to like well hey maybe you could
start your own weekly group and you know
maybe blah blah like you don't feel you
don't feel like you're um losing
something with the lack of community
there you feel like you're you're kind
of able to more like let's let's do the
solo philosopher thing for a while and
really just explore what I want to
explore yeah because I feel like if I
want it I'll find it I I just am an
extrovert so every time I've ever had a
hobby that nobody else wanted to do I
just went to a place where people did it
and I made friends so like if I ever
want to find people to think about this
or I want to talk to somebody
let's go find it you know
right
yeah and and now like I said I mean
there's like like that Meetup app or
whatever you can just hey I'm doing this
or hey I'm thinking about this book a
lot lately and it sucks rattling around
in my head anybody else want to talk
about it and make a little group and
meet up with people
yeah I've been uh really scared so I got
a corporate job already
and um I know I just have to eat dude
sadly
but
I was very scared of because my parents
work a lot like they have a very
calvinist Protestant view of work like
hard work like as a virtue and it's just
something that they are completely
willing to spend a lot of time and
effort in doing which is like labor is
an actualizing Force
right that's like inherently of value to
them and it's just not a value to me
like making because I just have a very
different view of the system that is in
place I mean the job I'm going to do is
fundamentally meaningless there's no
reason it needs to occur the only reason
it exists in society is so
like a number can go up like line go up
that's it that's why it's there it's
just to make somebody money so there's
nothing inherently freeing about that in
fact I would like to do
enough to make more money eventually but
I don't want to sell my time to that and
the prospect of selling my conscious
finite alive time to something that is
so fundamentally meaningless it was like
really uh it's really disconcerting I
guess but I've kind of shifted away from
that amount of nihilism because it's
just something that needs to occur and I
found that I can find actualization
outside of that
so yeah yeah you don't have to be such a
slave to it it doesn't inherently mean
like even if you are working a lot of
hours it doesn't it doesn't mean that
everything else has to back burner but
you do have to watch it if it does start
to happen
hello because it's like just American
culture to overwork we just are
inherently overworked so it's Hammer
works right you just get steeped in
working too much yeah I'm really gonna
try to fight that I found
um in his it gets kind of difficult to
wrestle with because I I would find
um the jobs I'm working on like it has
to have some sort of meaning for me
um and it like it's it's you know
inherently selfish but um like working
at UPS for example like I I told you
that before like it's just something
about it that just felt so off like
every day I felt like I was um like
disobeying
something truer in myself and and it's
like like and it's interesting because I
feel like there there is the side of me
you know the like the side that I've
built up of like dude that's maybe
that's your default but you've got to be
positive and look you are helping these
people and you're you know you're good
at your job and you're friendly to your
co-workers and you make people's job not
shitty and um you know you do a good job
and you should have pride in that
there's like all these things that like
I could kind of add to it but that's
that was like it's like this extra work
and I was forcing it there was no
natural like yeah this job this I have
meaning I give people their packages you
know what I mean like there's there's
nothing that I could find from that and
it was very um very draining and it made
it when I would get off work when I
wasn't working like
um
unfortunately it wouldn't like fuel me
up like okay now that I'm off work now I
could really work you know it felt like
it was more
um
I don't know it's difficult to line up
like purpose meaning a sense of
fulfillment you know when you when you
come to these conclusions about the
capitalistic world and then still like
try to have an actual sense of meaning
while working within it
yeah well it's just like inherently
meaningless
it is like the a lot of reason the jobs
happen and haven't been automated is
just so people can have something to do
to make money that's it because
capitalism is predicated on the fact
that you have to give money to people
that aren't Rich so they can buy your
product
so like so much stuff is just in so many
people's jobs are abstractly and in
reality don't need to occur and it is
impossible to escape that feeling
hmm I mean it so
it's just not great all-around not a
good time and it's a very Justified
feeling that you had too it's something
that you really can't you already you
like cats out of the bag you already
understand that right so the moment
you're trying to like abstract yourself
around it you are
I can't lie to myself like I can't trick
myself into stuff I know other people
can totally fine but I just can't do it
so yeah
yeah it's the uh Jordan Peterson has
actually talked about that like
um pretty elegantly you you can
like like if you want to know what truth
is like you know what truth is like it
doesn't matter what we're saying out
here you're like if you say something
untrue out here only you like you know
that it's untrue within here and there's
like there's repercussions in your
interior mind because of that
yeah it's just like living in
discordance with whatever your insides
feel which sometimes that just requires
a perspective shift and I actually think
that uh truth is relative to some degree
based on whatever like ideological lens
that you've been steeped in but there is
that feeling of even if it's technically
only true relative to you living not in
accordance to it it's definitely
detrimental
[Music]
um
well man well we've we've painted
ourselves into a depressing corner of
philosophical thoughts here
um what uh
what else do you have written down there
that you'd like to mention my friend oh
I mean actually so
was uh there was a man named um
Max Weber he wrote a book called uh
capitalism in the Protestant ethic so it
actually refers to kind of what I was
just talking about which is something
that you can see just inherently
throughout Society
so
hard work
is
a virtue
in uh Calvinism or modern Christianity
protestantism and it really propelled
capitalism for how it was like all of
the really hard hours and general abuse
that occurred was done on the backs of
the fact that the uh religious and
hegemonic belief system relied on the
fact that
hard work is something that is implicit
and really good
just with with out of context it's just
a thing that's good no matter what
you're working hard for it in itself is
a good thing to do interesting
but
uh post-modern capitalism what we're
experiencing now uh really relies on uh
Western Buddhism
it requires you to distance yourself
from the innovate meaninglessness of the
labor that's happening and this is a
it's just like how I said this eats
everything it's even eating Taoist
religion so you see a lot of
Corporations and uh
like hustle grinds and influencers
really into a really distorted not super
true version of Buddhism
yeah
okay yeah yeah keep going I actually
yeah you see I'm saying so it fulfills
the same role that Calvinism did in the
Industrial Age where hard work was
inherent now we have such a
psychologically grinding
um
condition that is attributed to work
that there is no way that you could
escape the fundamental meaninglessness
of this without engaging in a Eastern
philosophy that allows you to
disassociate from it radical acceptance
yeah because it just makes it easier
yeah you can get through the day you're
you're like draining children of
adrenochrome but you're you're like
like really though so why do you think
the Nazis used Buddhist iconography
so distant they had to find a way to
distance themselves and the soldiers
that were engaging in abject Horrors to
distance themselves from doing these
things and uh I heard a quote and it's
good men will do good things and bad men
will do bad things and religion will
make good men do bad things
because it's an ideological framework in
which that you now are allowed to do
necessarily whatever you want because
you
and that's and this is not a judgment on
Buddhism in any way in fact I think it's
rather quaint and beautiful in a ideal
form it's just more of an observation of
how things are yeah we are we are taking
little bits and pieces it's again
capitalism eating everything it's taking
little bits and pieces like yeah this
kind of makes sense here and inserts it
into where it loses its Essence but it
does kind of work within the bigger you
know pulsivity of the system and then it
also
um lends to the pacification too so if
we if Google can make your material
conditions immediately really
comfortable like hey here's a meditation
course do you want a soda you know well
we're going to work you 80 hours but
we're going to teach you how to
disassociate from that and then you're
going to feel comfortable like a frog
boiling in water and you're never going
to unionize
yeah so it's like a pacification
technique
so and that's uh the thinkers that I've
been listening to and reading have
really criticized ideology which just on
its own because it's like The Unbroken
Hammer it's the working hammer and it
acts as like glasses like a distortion
glasses where you cannot see anything
for what it really is because you were
steeped in ideology
how many more years do you think we have
of this like like realistically like do
you think we even have a hundred years
I don't really think about it I'm just
not having kids and I'm gonna enjoy my
life regardless of this I still actually
have mostly almost exclusively good days
and
for the little things but I have kids
and just raise a little Warlord
no no I'm I'm not down for that Max at a
young age yeah hopefully that ax breaks
and then he can get out of ideology but
unlikely yeah in the same boat it's hard
to uh
it's hard to fantasize
or hard to like
oh I hope that's gonna be all okay in a
sense
the problem is so if we can learn
anything from the
Russian Revolution which is
the only attempt to break free from
Global Capital like the entire Universal
market system
is that revolutions don't work
because they create a power vacuum and
it's just not the way to apply a more
egalitarian system because we got
stalinism out of that and that was
really bad
so but the contrary to that is because
Global Capital which is the entire
ingrained market system of the world is
reliant on everything else and you need
to participate to be a nation in it if
any Nation tries to
not do that or reorgan make a new base
right for that base super sure funnel
they try to make a new base uh they will
be
uh invaded usurped or excluded from all
Commerce
so because everything is so interlinked
it is impossible to break necessarily
unless it is like a total everybody that
isn't the top three percent decides that
we're not going to do it anymore like a
worldwide general strike which is not
going to happen which I do think is
potentially possible
but the problem is that hyper real
condition where
everybody kind of has like this weird
sense of reality and it's really
temporally distorted and nothing
necessarily means anything it's just
self-referential we can't really
conclude anything nobody can get on the
same page about the systems of
Oppression that are occurring and it's
very easy to propagandize to people so
eating consensus to decide collectively
that this shit's not that good is uh
very hard
yeah yeah and until then we kind of just
treat the treat the it's just symptom
management you know there's like these
little things that pop up like hey this
isn't right and then we've over focus on
that but it's uh they're really just you
know problems from the bigger system
yeah this is really depressing I
actually haven't really said all of this
out loud in one stream of Consciousness
but I'm actually so sorry no dude I I'm
not coming to it with much like um
optimism or um like any sort of like I
don't know Justice position or or
there's nothing there's nothing coming
from my end that's like super optimistic
on this particular day myself so yeah
but I just mean just in general like if
anyone's listening to this like hey if
it's nice out that's awesome you'll like
throw a frisbee like a lot of shit's
still great like you can still have a
good day regardless of this and you had
many good days your entire life and it
was this way
yeah I'm just like any listeners that
were planning on having children anytime
soon and probably bummed the [__] out
but um I mean that's kind of how it goes
I was thinking about that actually you
know with this podcast
like the the routes of it it started
with like like this like most vulnerable
show my heart to everybody and like you
know so vulnerable crying on the podcast
like here's what I'm going through and
then it's like uh well I'm gonna get
better and then it's like um what's
personal development what's self-help
and then it's like started going into
what self and then well so that opens up
philosophy well what are humans what's
got like it just start expanding you
know so it's it's just kind of
inherently where the podcast naturally
leads and you know starting talking
about like real real Philosophy from our
level of perception
um not just all sunshine and rainbows
and all like positive because because I
actually had a I had a couple people who
would like like refer to me as like the
positivity guy okay everything to do so
positive and I'm like what are you are
you like what are you listening to
because I'm not I'm not not always um
I don't know I I like to inherently I
like to to be optimistic when I can but
I think when it comes to philosophical
discussions like
philosophy gets in the goddamn way of of
having actual conversations sometimes
yeah with optimism does I mean well and
it doesn't help that the function of any
actual philosopher is to
criticize hegemonic systems which is
inherently uh sad degrading because it's
like hey here's how things are
well maybe they shouldn't be you know
especially uh modern philosophers I mean
obviously the first a thousand years of
philosophy was more like hey what's
existence you know and that's not really
sad that's kind of just interesting but
the further we get especially in like
modern philosophy it is mostly just a
criticism of
power structures
so which is like uh sad it's in it
becomes hard mentally sometimes
just because you learn all this [__]
about all these systems then you realize
that you're just like in them you know
it's not like this abstract thing it's
like oh I'm like I'm in it sick like I'm
living in it so yeah you you wake up
from the Matrix and you're like ah I'm
gonna step out and then you're like well
it's completely impossible like
everything I am and how I make all my
movements are within that so like you
gotta [__] kind of put your head back
down that is kind of how it is you're
like oh I'm I'm enlightened I know
everything I discovered that we're in
these systems and I could see what other
people don't see and then you're like
well to make any actual difference it's
going to take 10 years of me working
hard within the system to like it's it's
a it's a hilarious Cosmic joke in a
sense yeah and it's like inherently
quarter to write just because you uh
like whatever wake up I don't know
whatever cheesy what you want to say it
but uh
you still have to engage in all of the
systems to be alive
like you gotta like eat stuff you know
so I mean that's a funny thing and
that's how um the Buddha still farts
I apologize I'm getting over a sinus
infection so
congested as long as I can't contract it
through Zoom yeah but just kidding I
don't look at humans like they're germs
that's like something I definitely like
anytime anybody coughs now or Snee like
anything I go out of my way to say bless
you and stuff just because I feel like
covet left this like like you're your
disease I don't want to be near you when
someone sneezes so I'm always like hey
no we're humans we love each other
yeah it's funny because like more
inherently all gross like everybody's
got a butthole like it's like we're
gross like beings are dirty and that's
totally fine and uh I I thought about
this yesterday because I just saw this
Reddit video
it was just this guy and he was
definitely inebriated in some way and he
just like slowly started to vomit in a
public space like like really trying to
contain it I was like
I'm really disgusted by this but it's
like a just like a guy you know this
happened to everybody I don't know why
I've vomited many times but I'm so
disgusted by this happening like this
guy vomiting is grosser than me vomiting
it's not this is funny it is funny when
other people do something it's it's so I
mean even even us think about how
strange we are my spit in my mouth right
now like whatever but like if I were to
spit into a cup and then you say drink
your own spit now I would be like what
no way that's disgusting like we're so
weird the way that we kind of I don't
know if it's just like our understanding
of germs or understanding of um
I don't know if it's a social thing like
maybe that's a deeper social thing not
being able to drink our own spit
yeah well I actually just think a lot of
a lot of stuff like disgust in general
and you can see this because fetishes
exist that are like actually not clean
uh is learned behavior like most stuff
is learned behavior and culturally given
learn well okay but what about have you
seen um uh on like your mom's house
podcast with Tom Segura and Christina P
um they they have like people with
fetishes on like on their podcast and
they'll show the videos there's this one
guy that was I mean that's his thing he
was in like a [__] tank like a super
scatter some nuts dude yeah have you
seen that like he's literally just
rubbing himself in human feces and stuff
and that's like what he gets off on and
like how do you like how is that a
learned behavior you know like what how
do you learn that of whatever you are
observing it's not like he like his dad
did that when he was younger and he just
really loves his dad you know what I
mean
so Lacon is a predecessor to Freud or a
successor rather
and uh he talks about uh transference of
attributes to items in modernity like oh
so let's say you somehow have a like you
get to the point where you have a fetish
so now you now you like women's shoes
like those are those are attractive so
it's like you have this attribute
transfer to a thing that is technically
an object but it mentally to you holds
these attributes
so human desire is really interesting it
could be like oh I love asses oh I love
buttholes oh I love poop yeah now poop
on my chest I'll give you eighty dollars
you know
oh no I mean it's the amount of people
that probably are really into that is
probably way higher than we think
well the internet has allowed you to
pursue more and more emulation for
better for worse which I'm like totally
down for because like everybody just
like being more sexually open is like
cool because we're just more accepting
of stuff yeah but there is a negative to
that which is uh people pooping on each
other
that's the one I don't kink chain but
like if I'm gonna shame one cake like
please no poopy yeah it just seems you
know it's just I mean as far as the word
unsanitary goes it seems like a moderate
good definition of it
yeah I uh my stepdad has a story about
one of his friends who thought he had a
scat fetish
uh and then got some girl like willingly
didn't pay her who agreed to poop on his
chest and then the moment it touched his
uh oh it was his mouth the moment it
touched his tongue he realized he didn't
have a scat fetish and that's uh that's
hilarious to me like if that's like the
worst point of no return right you
couldn't have figured that out like 40
minutes ago you know I mean I guess if
you're really that like there's really
only way one way to know I you know
don't knock it till you try it but not
at least try it he can knock it you know
yeah that's the one the only one I'm
like nah I'm good
oh like I'll try anything but not that
yeah yeah I'm I'm in the same boat like
I'm not like immediately against
something but I guess I am immediately
against that like I don't think there's
any world where like no matter how much
I love this person like if that's what
they're into I just don't know that I'm
gonna
do anything but it I don't even know if
I want to endure it for them you know
because okay
even maybe
in like the Heat of the Moment you let
that happen there's like a five seconds
so you know it's like um it's like after
you finish right there's like some
clarity okay you get done even if you
like it you just have [__] on you like
somebody just pooped on you and I gotta
clean it up somebody actually pooped on
your chest and now you got to deal with
it for probably a while yeah that's how
comfortable like what do you like you
got [__] on your chest in your bed like
you can't just stand up and go to the
bathroom oh you got to put a tarp down I
know you're doing like an inflatable
bathtub or something you got this is a
garage activity you gotta set this whole
thing up in there uh as the great
philosopher Lil Wayne would say as soon
as I come I come to my senses
foreign
what else has been on your mind lately
Spencer is is that that pretty much
where you're at like what have you been
finding yourself studying you said
you've been kind of like leaning into
things that just you just you enjoy how
you've been letting the um the wonderful
overlords of of algorithms on YouTube
overtake your choices and just explore
what's on there have you been reading
anything that's jumping at you actually
no so I've been reading simulator
lockerman simulation by Jean Polo guard
and then
um
the whole paper that I wrote actually
sent me on this weird goose chase to
figure out how all these ideas are
connected because a big part of modern
philosophy is the fact that it's kind of
referential on a bunch of other stuff
that's already happened like
if you go read like slavoyag's uh
Sublime object of ideology there's like
in the first six paragraphs there's like
seven references to a bunch of other
thinkers that have full long books and
thoughts so it's like
okay I can't even get to this I need to
go I need to go back further figure out
where it came from so I've kind of just
been working backwards whenever I find
somebody I figure out where they are
where they got inspired
yeah because they'll maybe say it and
then I will go figure out how that
informs their world view and then it
deepens my understanding for what
they're saying it is philosophy is very
much the standing on shoulders of giants
sort of thing like every time I think
that I have kind of an original idea I
think there's somebody who has thought
about it so much long ago and they've
thought about it and then like all of
their predecessors have thought about it
and written about it and yeah it's it's
it's strange to think that you'd have an
original idea in philosophy nowadays I
pretty much relented to even being smart
in general like it's just like not a
thing that I am and it's mostly just
because of well I'm sure some actual
genuine attributes of just like not
being brilliant you know just like a
regular guy one two these people are
like doctorates and they've spent
literally their entire lives reading all
of this like a real and enough to have
their own thoughts synthesis and maybe
even ideas to reference on their own
so
just comprehending that is now enough
even comprehending it a little bit is
what I've accepted you know like
anything that would change my world view
but I would think is good no matter what
my level of total comprehension is
compared to them like I just have
relented to never I'll never be as smart
or understand as well as they do that's
totally fine thankfully they wrote stuff
down do you have any sort of
I don't know how true it is in my brain
but I do have this thing in the back and
maybe I just like keep the candle
burning because it somehow motivates me
or it's some sort of like here's why I'm
spending so much time doing this and it
makes it okay do you have any sort of um
thoughts about like you know what in the
future
10 20 15 30 years from now I'm gonna
write something or or have discussions
with people that are that are worthwhile
in the in the philosophy world like
again it's you know self-important so we
all but there is still sort of some sort
of like self-belief of
um that I almost find myself
a lot of it is to justify why I'm
spending so much time in philosophical
thought
because it's like well why don't I like
you know work on my finances like why
don't I get some more gigs like why
don't I like try to get a girlfriend why
don't I work on getting a dog like of
all these things that I could be doing
um that could like bring my life
fulfillment
like why am I studying philosophy a lot
of times I find myself like thinking
okay you know what maybe I'll just have
to even if it's not true I'm gonna put
this thing out that it's going to be
helpful later in my life or like it'll
make sense or I don't know do you have
anything like that or is it more of just
I try to just be where I'm at and study
philosophy and I don't care like what it
assumes to I don't know so I have been
plugged and characterized by having
lofty ideals for what I want to do in
general like I'm gonna do a lot of
things I'll say it because it's like a
really fun idea to play with right like
I'm gonna write something someday I'm
gonna create something I'm gonna do x no
matter how big or how small it is
but uh it rarely ever happens you know
it's just I think this is kind of a
human thing but I genuinely don't really
try to assign any inherent value or
meaning to any of it monetarily because
it's just the exploratory process in
general I just I'm curious and I like it
it's really stimulating it's something
that I enjoy a lot and the feeling when
you finally hear something that is just
like shattering is just like oh
oh my Micah like it's just like having
your eyes refreshed all the time it's
just really on its own
devoid of outside influence something
that I just like that's it that's just
how I am people like other stuff that's
cool no that's good I it actually
reminds me uh I saw this Tick Tock that
was talking about uh it was like a gen Z
like an older gen Z person or something
and he was like um if you if you call my
hobbies a side hustle I'm gonna punch
you in the throat or something like that
he's like absolutely side hustle is
something that late stage Millennials
made up to justify their time and
everything what they're doing it was a
funny joke but it kind of hit me I'm
like oh God here I am trying to like
justify all the time like here I'm
spending my time on this and it's not to
enjoy life it's so it has this bigger
goal and it's it's like I'm like
sometimes even that so
that's the hammer breaking right so
that's you've been implicitly told by
the ideology of society and the implicit
structures that um the market system
creates to my time equals value which is
not true time does not equal money time
is time time is a finite resource and
whatever you want to do with that does
not need a price tag on it like it
actually it being devoid of money is
really enriching on its own so it almost
it's so it's like a degrading thought to
think that I would need to assign
a monetary value that I am losing to
something that I like I just enjoy you
know I think it ruins it and it makes it
hard I'm sure you can like
um or lay this or you feel this way as
well yeah like
if I thought yesterday I spent four
hours playing Total War Warhammer 2 and
listening to slavoy's gizek
I lost four hundred dollars that sucks
but it was a really fun thing to do I
really liked it but if I assigned money
to it it makes it like uh meaningless I
feel bad I feel guilty for it I just
don't do that just try my best to never
do that
yes I could technically be more
productive but what is I mean is
productivity even the value I am trying
to attain
yeah it's like an over focus on your
your legacy is like this um like
self-help entrepreneur like
um kind of like weird sickness of like
what like what are you gonna get there
bud like you're gonna arrive you know
you're gonna happen where's the
destination though you know I mean the
self-help industry has been co-opted by
people that are just trying to
uh make more money so like it's so much
of that that Buddhist thought that's
actually so pure and beautiful and
untainted has just been like here's how
you can have mental Wellness to grind
harder babies that's Sigma Grant said I
wake up at 3am and I Edge for punishment
and then I meditate for eight hours and
then I Edge For Pleasure send six emails
I mean all right we're not the same I
have been stuck in this uh so I so I
will say I've actually been a fan of
like the self-help self like I mean
since since I was a teen I think just
just my life of kind of this oh [__]
there's no but there's no adults like
taking care of you you got to figure out
how to do [__] like at a young age kind
of made me like really obsessed with a
lot of the self-development self-help
stuff but self-help books I remember
when it was just like such a small
section in the library
um and now it's like the you know the
front book section over Fantasy A lot of
the times is like the self-development
sort of thing so it's it's been cool
it's been very helpful in so many ways
but I also having been part of that
scene for so many years and like you
know I've I've read all the you know
most most like the popular books in the
self-help world it's um
definitely not all
um but but I've read every self-help
book
I have yes
oh God sometimes I say the stupidest
[__] and I'm like you're so full of
yourself like listening backwards too oh
God but it's uh I I do see how it's How
it changed and how we could be a slave
to it and I also really love you know
the um like the backwards a lot of the
Alan Watts would say like if you
if you um are someone who needs these
self-help books you're kind of
reciprocating the problem you're kind of
telling yourself that you're in lack of
you know and there's kind of this
balance of accepting who you are wanting
to get better and and learn new things
and stuff and a lot of times
self-development books in the self-help
world is kind of like that route and
that's amazing but there almost comes a
time where it's like you know quit
reading the books and go try it out and
yeah well there's also that feeling so I
keep talking about like hegemonic
ideologies maybe the ideal that you are
trying to be well to is uh fictitious
you know like you have an ideal that you
are trying to achieve and you've been
conditioned by Society Aid to think that
you currently are not meeting that which
is why all of them are centered around
productivity because that is that's
what's prized is you make make the line
go up so you feel the void of something
that is not inherently valuable or
necessarily good or part of you because
society's communicated that to you so
maybe that is not really what's broken
and trying to fix that symptom is not
really going to fix it which makes sense
why people would just endlessly read
self-help books to be more productive
but still sad you know
yeah I mean it just I see where it like
reifies you know old stories too where
where like even just like me me reading
a new self-help book like and re
revivifying the story of oh I'm I'm Jake
who had to learn it on his own and and
it's just like it's sometimes it's
stopping you from being who you really
are today and it's just kind of like
rewriting you into just the next chapter
of the story you made up about yourself
and your life well and we can even go
back to how the Nazis used Eastern
symbology and thoughts to disassociate
from
um like horrible atrocities so just
because you figure out or
to engage with any of these ideas
doesn't inherently make you a good
person that has good ethics values and
moral systems it's just somebody who
figured out how to disassociate like be
mindful that doesn't inherently make you
any better per se and it's it's still a
good thing to pursue but everybody's
seen there's like a lot of signaling
that goes on the internet with this as
well the person that all of a sudden is
enlightened on your feed but it's like
subtly the worst person you've ever
you've ever met in real life
you know so it's like you're kind of
fictitiously telling yourself like oh
you know I read X book I'm so much
better and then it's an excuse to just
engage in all the behavior you once did
so there's like no one real ticket to
getting better or like being better that
it can just be found in like a book I do
think that one Watts the books are very
beautiful though he was like a really
pure thinker well I mean I I think like
the core of like we both read wisdom of
insecurity and I think that like if
there could be a book that's kind of
like the book like the the
um seeing through the illusion of the
self is really kind of like the core of
the whole thing it's kind of the core of
um
I don't know even just so prolific I
heard somebody say recently like the
sign of just like a potent and really
good educator is somebody that can say
something in a way
that coalets is a bunch of stuff you
already implicitly understood
in a new way that you could have never
synthesized and reading that book is
just like I know this I already know
what it is I can feel this is how I feel
in words that are just like beautifully
poetic the prose is perfect it's paced
incredibly and it's just exactly just
the modern condition in like a very
interesting way and that's why I just
think that he touches a lot of people
because of that feeling
yeah I I mean I that's exactly what it
is it's not you're not learning
something new you're
you're remembering and you're also
unlearning through that remembering and
it's this weird thing that and it's also
on I mean it's on a spiritual level
um yeah I know that word is just so
sticky but it's on a spiritual level
because it
um
it
it shows you what you really are as it
reminds you of what you're not and shows
you kind of
where you were thinking incorrectly like
like where you you where your
understanding of yourself is getting in
the way of like it's making you suffer
essentially
yeah
it's a
I don't know I still come back to a lot
of Alan Watts he's still I mean probably
one of my favorite philosophers I still
consistently listen to a lot of his
lectures
um Sam Harris on his waking up app
actually just added like 17 lectures
um from from the backlog of Alan Watts
um and I've heard most of them before
but it's so nice to just have that at my
fingertips all the time
I'm just really glad that he was alive
right at the time in which that audio
recording became pretty good because
it's not only
what he says and writes it's just the
way that he speaks like the whole
presentation and package really just
like adds to everything he was just
great just really prolific dude it
really makes me want to teach with a
chalkboard like I just want to teach
people while I have a chalkboard with me
because there's so many of them you can
see like if you see any videos he's you
know he's drawing simple things little
stick figures or a little feather a
little bird or whatever to like kind of
um you know hold space for his points
and those little visualizations probably
help the crowd you know understand
things a lot really well and then you
can kind of hear the chalk hitting the
hitting the board and a lot of the audio
lectures and just makes me want to uh
write things with chalk or a whiteboard
so I think romdas actually does really
well I spent a lot of time listening to
ramdas too like kind of um he is he is
more on the spiritual like he he would
say you know he he teaches the path of
love
um and then he famously followed a guru
up but he his his talks are kind of the
same thing and uh or or gangaji if
you've ever heard of her they're
like it's literally just a remembering
like the crowd is So Silent the crowd is
listening the crowd isn't really like
intellectualizing or like well how does
that work and how does that work it's
it's this just listening and like
feeling what they're telling you about
the human condition and it unwinds all
the questions that you thought you had
and so it's a it's a reminding reminding
rather than a
new information so it's almost something
like we know inherently in our psyche as
as humans it's just part of being a soul
Vessel we're being reminded of by this
like not self
features that we hear from these people
yeah it's um I feel really interesting
about that feeling because I'm just not
an essentialist
like um what do you mean essentialism
would be like there is a metaphysical
it's kind of what uh I think that young
thought this there's like a metaphysical
Essence to a man or a woman or ex thing
that is like ethereal and like true and
un
unbending it's you can see a lot of like
neo-spiritual movements especially in
the west like Aubry Marcus will use a
lot of language that's essentialist like
um
it honestly operates on like a binary a
lot so like
men are older women or chaos stuff like
that I just don't think that that is
fundamentally true but it's always
interesting to listen to people who say
stuff and you feel it right like you
feel like this is inherent to The Human
Condition which affronts um
essentialist which is kind of an
essential thought in a way so it's just
always interesting for me to um engage
with stuff like that because it's like
impactful and I can't really figure out
why
right yeah but it but it is difficult of
of the words don't quite do it and there
is like a lot of ways that you can kind
of dispute the words it's like well like
what you're saying doesn't really make
sense but I do kind of get what you mean
is is a lot of where that area goes you
you were talking about I had sent you
the other day um clips from Rebel or a
video from Rebel wisdom weren't you
saying something about like you were
recently thinking about about their um
their Channel what was that for was that
yeah so I have been trying to figure out
so in the in America
there is a like Christian fundamentalism
just kind of lies at the base of a lot
of things and structures that we believe
whether you are a Christian or not it is
just like Max Weber and the Protestant
ethic right it's just like ingrained in
the way that we have Society like you're
steeped in the ideology
and in movements or people that usually
detract from social movements uh trans
rights stuff like that
um just a
left-leaning uh workers movements
they all are really disparate so like
Jordan Peterson is a
um he's just like a Christian
conservative so he detracts from that
and he has a lot of essentialist thought
Aubry Marcus has some detracting from
that and he's part of the Neo spiritual
movement
and I just found that in a lot of these
people like in maybe an IDW there's just
I was trying to figure out a through
line because they seem very disparate in
their total thought process but they all
kind of coalesce to fight against a lot
of this stuff and I determined that
it's just a centralist thought to some
degree so it's like there's a real
metaphysical Essence to
gender or
um Humanity in general like it's on a
materialist thought like we have a soul
there's a specific Essence to all things
and it rely it's on like an astral realm
it's like the young Ian ID or the
Freudian idea of that
and uh I wanted to know about their
Channel because when I engage with them
maybe years ago
I thought that they uh were the most
reasonable of the rationals the Skeptics
because there's a lot of skeptic thought
that is kind of just like [__] heady on
YouTube well you're just gonna get it
but they just seemed
so coherent yet I disagreed with them in
so many ways so I was just intrigued
more than anything
yeah the uh David Fuller used to work
for like one of the major news networks
he's like one of the main guys of the
channel uh yeah you work for BBC I'm
pretty sure I looked it up after we
talked yeah and so he's he's very
logical and he's I think he's um as far
as you know journalistic Integrity goes
or even just
um kind of like uh you know just for
lack of a better term like the essence
of what a journalist should be I feel
like he kind of like it's a thing of
importance to him he doesn't get caught
up by all like the all this stuff that
comes with being a journalist or like a
news reporter nowadays this just seems
to really miss the point and it seems to
you know like you said be be captured by
capitalism just too much to actually be
an Arbiter of Truth or real useful
information it's just so painted with
bias so I just feel like um
yeah I I have liked a lot of his stuff
like I was saying I you know the last I
don't know with a lot of like the the
you know
um
pandemic stuff and a lot of like the
Ukraine stuff I just I didn't really I
didn't I didn't like their opinions very
very much I don't know I just I feel
like they kind of got caught and caught
in the web of things
you have a very interesting perspective
on a lot of this too because I've just
found that you just like don't like
um
I don't like conflict very much in these
in these spaces like a non-uh agreeance
and solution based response so is that
is that what's occurring here
yeah probably I mean I I naturally do
not like conflict just just as my person
I actually avoid conflict which is
actually like a detriment to my um
personality and relationships sometimes
but but I I to me
I'm just about Solutions and I know that
sounds like douchey but it's like when
there's a problem if it's a real problem
let's not stroke each other feeling good
about pointing out the problem like
let's talk about a solution what's next
and I don't know uh it seems like a
waste of time a lot of times to get
caught up too into the weeds and like
well you're I don't know
and I think to some degree it is uh
the political climate of
modernity is um
it's hard because opposing uh factions
fundamentally have different values and
see the world differently enough to
where it would be uh I think impossible
to actually
have one have a solution because just
the value structure and the way the
thought is produced is just not close
enough
yeah you'd have to have a same end goal
yeah and it's just like the fundamental
aims and goals of many disparate
factions are different enough and a lot
of these a lot of times propaganda
stoking the fire of all of this or just
causing friction because they don't want
you to look at something else
but um
I think the consensus is not a thing
that happens anymore but I will say I
think a lot of my perspective
this sounds so cheesy I think a lot of
my perspective comes from like
this like the answer is love sort of
thing like at the core of whatever
you're fighting about cool at the core
whatever arguing about cool but like
what what is a human what's Humanity
like what what do we need to get
together what's actually important like
like not through the labels not through
the the menu of like bullet points of
things that are important
um you know even even Beyond like our
hierarchy of needs
um or maybe even like not far removed
from it like the answer
I don't know like I I understand that
I'm like very far detached from like we
do have to solve the problem so it does
have to be discussion there does have to
be like boots on the ground like this we
can't just all decide to sit on the
ground crisscross applesauce and it's
all solved I get that but uh I don't
know a lot of times the things to me I
don't even become involved with them
when I see other other thing other
people arguing about specifics
I'm just like I don't think anything
that you're talking about or any of the
ways in which you're talking about have
anything to do with like the overall
goal of what Humanity should be thinking
about which is you know the same like uh
you know a a b is is collecting honey
for for the hive you know like we have
some sort of humanitarian there's some
sort of something that brings us all
together and we have some sort of One
Direction we should be going let's say
that's love
if you're talking about things that
aren't pointing in the direction of that
then it's just almost pointless to me
so yeah I think that feels really good
but
like a lot of nuanced stuff to occur and
a lot of factions are inherently
exclusionary
where it's like people that
I mean just any racism that would ever
occur uh anybody that thinks anybody
that lives outside of the country is any
less of a person deserving of actual
like actualization and love is uh it's
for art right and there are real
factions that believe that so that is
inherently a philosophy and ideological
thought process that is not grounded
upon love itself so the only way to
fight that would be to deter from it
right so like conflict is even if that's
your goal it is just going to be a need
to The Human Experience and I know it
feels like [__] I don't want to happen
either I think it's fundamentally
necessary
yeah I mean it's completely I completely
agree you can't have
you can't just avoid conflict at all
times but a lot of times I I think we're
throwing chairs at each other when we
could be talking absolutely I just think
that
um
there's some fundamental
misunderstandings
that are innate that really don't help
that are also fueled by the media
process as well
like
the blatant misuse of terminology by
your political opposition to Buddy the
ideological Waters so you don't actually
have to contend with their ideas
happens a lot like the misuse of words
like uh post-modernism like as a thought
process like that is blatantly misused
all the time to detract or deter from
ever having to actually engage with any
of these ideas and uh D faces uh anybody
that would try to talk about them in the
political sphere so not only are we
having fundamental differences between
factions or having a actual and
concerted effort to undermine uh the
what signs and symbols mean and if we go
back to like what the the hyper real
setting that we're in they already are
completely muddied in general so like
fundamentally words have to mean stuff
because language is Clumsy but it's the
only tool we have
but everything that is just occurring is
it making a concerted effort whether
it's implicit or explicit
to have the symbols and signs not mean
anything
yeah it is a pretty big deal like for
you know for me to say snowflake
um and for us to be and I'm not even
talking about like the political what
they would call like people snowflakes
I'm saying like like act like in a
blizzard snow a snowflake like you
picture when I say snowflake what Pops
in your head like the little you know
dimensional whatever snowflake or an
actual just piece of snow like
regardless of the word we need to be
able to know the same thing as we're
saying the word to even be able to
communicate and like make sense of
um reality really and when we're we're
at a point where I don't know if it's
just because of the internet or it's
like really sped up by the internet
we're at a point where we're saying the
exact same words it's the same mouth
movements but it's not reciproc it's
it's not
you know proliferating or creating the
same image within our heads like we're
thinking something completely different
you know when we say the same words and
some of these words are
you know like like they have a lot with
them they have you know when someone
like the words like racism and stuff you
know it's it's
there's a lot that comes with it there's
a lot of baggage that comes with it but
it might not be the same meaning to
every single person who hears the word
and it's definitely not and you can
actually see this so I talk to my
professor about this why uh Progressive
movements in general actually have a way
harder time uh on a rhetorical level
than conservative movements
because Progressive movements are
usually light on the back of a lot of
philosophical thought Theory and a
really intense academic literature that
requires a lot of explaining forward
thought in a really specific language
and conservative movements are usually
really easy to understand and they
usually hearken back to times that have
already passed or Nostalgia as a tool or
really things that appease people that
feels innate to them like
stuff that would appeal to Common Sense
stuff that appeals to uh whatever the
hegemonic ideology is stuff that when
you hear you don't question it because
it sounds bright so if I like say well
if we allow immigration people are going
to take our jobs because more people
need jobs it's like fundamentally
there's like a long economic process so
why that's actually not why we have a
problem but it sounds right yeah so the
the problem with progress
is a you get caught explaining it's too
easy to divert in the longer and more
complex society goes on the harder and
harder it is to do that
so it's hard to make progress on like
I'm just a basic debate rhetorical level
you just get caught explaining
yeah yeah yeah it gets always getting
caught you know far farther into the
weeds and less farther away from like
the meaning because I gotta like so
let's see so if I will take racism for
example
there is a sect of people that believe
that uh Martin Luther King who has
become a defanged symbol of himself who
was actually a revolutionary thinker and
has become just like a symbol of like
peace and racism ended right black
people can vote now racism is over
people think that because all the laws
are the same it's really easy to
comprehend that it's a very easy to
position to take and it actually feels
good right that makes you feel good yeah
racism's over look we're all equal but
the explaining the sociological
socioeconomic and philosophical
implications of like modern racism takes
like full courses
so one of these things feels good easy
to comprehend one of them feels like
[__] super hard to understand a lot of
nuance right so which one of these is
going to be the common idea the one
that's easy and feels good it's just
like part of humanity because we just
have this thing called cognitive
miserliness where you evolve to survive
and conserve energy and your brain takes
up 20 of the calories of your body every
day so if you can ever
Outsource an idea this is just an
evolutionary process you can Outsource
an idea and then stop thinking about it
just put in a box it is evolutionary
advantageous
thinking is counter to The Human
Experience
in a way
I think blame Falls in that category too
like we want to find a person to blame
like who is who is at fault for this it
feels good to find like there they are
let's put it all this stuff that's
chaotic that hurts my arms to carry
because my arms are weak I just want to
put it on them and that's blame and it
kind of kind of Falls in that same
category we just want that one thing
like it's this it's it's that's why
minorities are a good scapegoat for
movements that would use them because
instead of explaining the socio-economic
pressures of a neoliberal market
fundamentalism I can just say minorities
take your jobs
you know like one of those super easy to
understand and it feels better I'm sure
because it's like uh people that don't
look like me their fault you know it's
not
the whole hegemonic complex structure of
global capital and all of these small
implicit details of the ideology I've
been steeped in my entire life
actually brown people yeah that's that
all that other stuff is a lot of work I
like that I like the easy feels good
solution
so
and people are rightfully mad about
stuff that's kind of the problem with
movements that would divert social
antagonism to minorities or any
protected class of people because it's
taking a really real feeling right
economic insecurity a lack of
actualization Society is obviously not
made for you to survive or thrive in you
just are a puppet to many things and you
don't have a lot of agency
and so instead of taking that energy and
diverting it somewhere where it can
change you just divert towards
minorities
and now you can stop minorities from
gaining progress in society which is
usually your political goal as well and
you divert all the political antagonism
away from the Oil Barons
you know
it's easy it's easier to do so it's like
uh having consensus is hard because
there's like a lot of Bad actors
yeah I mean I suppose
it's just small in increments it's it's
just like
one step forward two steps back sort of
stuff when it comes to like really
understanding it and somehow explaining
it to people where it like makes sense
to them and we could stop making the
same
you know kind of mindless mistakes like
the like the
the way that we solve problems like
running it running it through the ways
that have not been working and just
continually trying the same thing yeah I
think it'd be foolish just even think
that anybody that is a part of any
system that is in control including
billionaires actively even trying to
solve anything because the system is
obviously working as intended
right now I mean they make a lot of
money all the time they have all the
power like why would change actually why
would they want it to occur like this is
working as intended mm-hmm
well now we live in our deterministic
universe we live in a deterministic
economy
um okay well
we're creeping up uh towards the
two-hour Mark here Spencer I do want to
let's just like crazy man I know like
what have we what it just it just
happens so quick
um I was thinking like just to go meta
on
like our our conversations I mean like
when we have these on the podcast like
if they're inherently philosophical like
we both enjoy studying philosophy
um you are actually an academic in
philosophy I'm just a turd who like
listens to audiobooks and YouTube
lectures and reads random [__] and
thinks about stuff
um but like I don't know like what
thinking about like the future of
I don't know I don't want to say like
how can we make our conversations
helpful like because I'm kind of over
this like I'm Gonna Save the World
I mean I'm not like I kind of like
there's a naive side of me that's like I
want to hold on to this at all times of
like I could save the world because I
like that delusional I like that that
Cockiness I like that self-importance
like sometimes sometimes it like fuels a
little bit of my artistic side and uh
I don't know but I don't want to get too
caught up in it like like how do we how
do we continue to have these
conversations and why should we continue
to have these conversations and what are
some things we could be thinking about
to discuss in the future
I don't know what I've decided as my
goal because
into the face of everything I've just
said it seems like you're you don't have
a lot of agency to do a lot of change
right
um
people talk about doing direct action a
lot and I think that's really that's
really good like if you have um
you want to stand up for Trans rights or
and just any anything like actual go
helping in a community is like a really
good thing to do any anything that you
want whatever your political leading is
you want to go help with a church like
they'll be active in your community
that's great
but I think because uh ideology is just
so like effervescent and prevalent and
we're all just so steep in it the best
thing that I could do if I ever have a
public square is to try to break the
hammer try to have somebody take the
glasses off take a step back maybe we
can look at the structures that are
making life really hard and maybe I make
you think about it that's it I think
that out of all the things that I could
do realistically that's not really that
materially helpful but
like just getting away from the way
things are mentally thinking about it
that's that's what I'm going to try to
do I think that that's like a pretty
small thing to want and um
you could ever because I really love it
when it's shattered right when you
finally get to take the glasses off just
if anybody if I could ever get anybody
to do that in any way make you say huh
maybe I really took this as an implicit
truth but
it's just a social Constructor maybe
maybe it's not true maybe there's
another way maybe there's a better way
maybe we can look at this through a
different lens
well I think that's a relatively noble
cause
okay yeah fair and I do I feel like that
is kind of what we do in these
conversations it is kind of a I do
because maybe it's normal for us to come
to these conclusions or maybe somewhere
for us to like circle around these like
subjects but a lot of the people
listening perhaps have never even heard
of any of this stuff before and so
they've never even thought about it
they've never really like questioned
where they're at within it and uh it's
not to say like
we're trying to be the Arbiters of Truth
or trying to be the ultimate Problem
Solver but I think yeah if you have a
Public Square do what you can in your
Public Square like I'm nothing more than
exactly who the hell I am
yes yeah I guess just the attempt is
like
you are taking you know like we were
talking about the beginning you're going
through your days and everything you see
is just like implicitly occurring you
find it to be true it's a thing that
exists
it's unwavering it's a real concrete
object or idea
but probably not all the systems and
structures that you ever engage with
were deliberately constructed they can
be revoked they're sulfur constructs and
honestly everything that you would deem
a capital T true is lowercase true and
they're relatively is another truth or
thing that could exist in the same space
just need to look a little further away
everything is was put there and can be
subject to change and if it is something
that is causing you pain or any system
that is detracting from your life
it would be bad to look at it like a
concrete reality truth
even even when we come to like edges of
nihilism it's so exciting to like like
that's the
like
it's inherently exciting to discover and
learn these things like even though like
even there is a little bit of where like
you know your ego or like your sense of
self is like whoa hey you're pushing
against me like I thought I was solid
and now I don't feel very solid but it's
very interesting keep going it really is
so exciting too like that's a like maybe
it's almost like selfishly for me too I
really like doing this stuff I like
having these conversations because it's
like
it makes me feel all tingly inside it's
the unknown too right I mean there are
people people have certain propensities
for stuff like some people just see
Comfort they like the security I've
always just liked chaos and the unknown
so just kind of like we flinging
yourself metaphysically through whatever
is going to be as deconstructive as
physically possible it's like super
titillating that's just like not for
everybody that's totally fine but I
don't know I like to do it
yeah I like the oh [__]
maybe everything I know is for sure
wrong
to being wrong I realized that I think
that I'm wrong about determinism
something I talked about this earlier
something that I have like been fairly
certain on in myself for a while it was
cool like damn
that's awesome because I just don't like
the idea of
okay I found an idea I think is true and
then it's just like that's it right yeah
it's the edge of that is always the fun
part it's not the finding it it's
defining the next thing I I love when
you um like you you learn of a
philosopher an author or like somebody
or an intellectual and like for a couple
years you almost believe everything they
say you're like dude that's exactly what
I believe and then I love the part that
comes afterwards we start to like hear
them say things where you're like I
don't [__] believe in that and then
you start to cheat like actually I can
actually kind of think differently about
that thing that I was really sturdy
about when he said it three years ago I
think I'm finding that um a lot with
like Sam Harris like the first few years
of me discovering Sam Harris
it was like everything he was saying I'm
like there's some truth in this and I
completely believe it and then he would
I'm starting to like have my own idea
and it's it's basically saying I'm
learning more and like kind of coming up
with my own opinions that are like
negating what people that I thought were
on the Forefront like on this pedestal
like I'm probably never gonna like
unthink anything like that it's so fun
to like unwind something that you
believe so so heavily for a little while
yeah so oh actually the whole IDW so
before I was political or did a lot of
thinking I really because they say a lot
of stuff that seems like common sense
and they're pretty confident so it's
really easy to eat up right if you don't
have the pretext
or the out exterior thought around it I
went from generally agreeing with them
because they were agreeable and I didn't
really know a lot to I actively disagree
with almost everything that they believe
and say
and it's um
and it's fun because you go from like
steeped in it to all criticism and it's
like a fun Evolution it was like a
growth path and they changed too maybe
you actually do agree with them or eight
years ago
too like you go look at their old stuff
you're like this is way more agreeable
well and it's I mean I think it's
like not believing all of what they say
or believing all of what they say is
just like you know nobody's really gonna
do that anyway
um I mean I guess I just said like at
the beginning I was like eating up a lot
of it but um you know what I was
actually thinking about I was going to
tell you this I I think a lot of my like
love and Fascination for the IDW was
almost what they tried to represent like
almost because like I think Eric
Weinstein was the ideal dude gave them
the name which you know it instantly
like ruins it but it is like for me
again as a you know just living back to
my story of this kid who like didn't
learn everything I Learned was like I
want to learn this because it wasn't
like it wasn't like oh I had to go it
was forced to go to class or whatever
like everything that I learned I'm
choosing to learn it and so for me to
feel like I stumbled across these like
intellectuals on YouTube that I could
like actually listen to and actually
learn something from and I mean really
just looking at the fact that there's
like sold out audiences to go watch
intellectuals speak on a stage wow
that's so cool like what like what a
cool thing and like for me to like
notice from a meta perspective like what
a cool thing for me to like get into and
like genuinely have interest in at like
26 27 years of age like I think this
this seems really cool I really like
being a part of this whole thing where
I'm one of the people in the audience
who's like huh listening and thinking
about what like the real really smart
professors are saying and maybe maybe
it's a lot of I didn't go to school so I
didn't ever actually like see actual
professors teaching a class I never
actually got really any of that like
connection and so maybe it's like in
place of that like academic you know uh
thriving or like wanting of something
like that's kind of what IDW like filled
for me that like you you've now been
through school like you had a connection
real connection with one of your
teachers and I'm sure like you know it's
somewhere similar around what I was like
searching for yeah it's kind of cool and
honestly so I went through a phase where
I definitely really enjoyed all of them
listen to all their stuff you know and
um I fundamentally disagree with myself
last year every year and I don't
discount and even if I objectively hate
everything that I thought five years ago
I don't discount that it was important
for me in the chain of thoughts to get
to where I am now although yeah good
like
um usually Eric and Jordan Peterson
usually their whole thing is something
that like I am really fundamentally
critical of now like I really honestly
detested in a lot of ways it was
fundamental for me to get to here in
general
like just the the process of curiosity
was important
so
that was good yeah and the symbol of
them is cool too like the idea they
represent more than themselves is like
um being an Arbiter of logic or being an
Arbiter of something that is being
unspoken right that inherently feels
good whether that's even happening or
not is it really not the point it's just
like
it's like a young kid because I was a
very old that's probably like 1819 it
like feels cool yeah sounds good there
there's something about right right like
just like we were talking about the
beginning there's something punk rock
about it like there's something like
about these guys you know in the you
know even like Sam Harris before like he
would call him and the other atheists
like the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse
or some [__] like that I actually love
Sam Harris atheist pick he's very
anti-islam for some very probably less
than silly reasons but I still agree
with him a lot in some ways he's he's so
he's so mixed up in things that I just
don't understand a lot of the times he's
like so yeah he's lost in the sauce no
yeah but I I will say man his his app is
just getting better and better the
waking up app like yeah to use that it's
great it's so good like he he
continually adds more and more stuff to
it he has some um you know some that are
from it's like old advice but he has
this woman read it who's like uh she's
she's some level of enlightened for sure
um I forget her name
I'm gonna forget your name but um she's
wonderful like her voice is wonderful so
it's it sounds really nice they made the
recordings nice they have like some
music in the background she reads these
texts but you you treat them like a
meditation so like you you'd sit in the
morning or I'm gonna sit for 30 minutes
unmoving while I listen to like this
wonderful woman read this text and it's
um and kind of explaining like what you
are and what you are not and you know
you know getting through the illusory
self in real time through these texts so
anyway it's it's it's very fun I'm
really liking where it's going I have a
lot of respect for Sam Harris in the app
yeah that's the best one and honestly
like
even though I Sam Harris is less
egregious but even though you detract
from somebody's whole political or
ideological worldview in some places
that doesn't mean that other stuff they
do that is good isn't good
right right like that app and all the
stuff that he does on it is objectively
awesome right you don't it's it's not
like a binary right like some stuff
people do great I'm something not great
it's like part of being a person
yep it's it's a it it reminds me all the
time of any time I'm insecure about like
I'll put out you know One Clip or like
here's here's one minute of my
conversation with Spencer here's one
minute of my conversation on like you
know the word God or the word spiritual
like I'll put that out there and I'm
like god dude like no someone is going
to have like this is all they're gonna
see of me this is all they're gonna know
of me and this is their whole opinion of
me and like sometimes overthink about
that but I just mainly remember like oh
that's literally just the way it is like
that's up for them if they want to have
that that oh I know everything about
this person because I saw this one clip
or if they don't want to accept other
things that they may like or dislike
about a person then
it's just it's interesting so I actually
I faced this uh all the time in my own
life so I'm you I'm like about 225
pounds like 11 to 10 about 12 body fat
like I look like a meathead most of the
time I just don't look like I would be
somebody that is reflective in any way
you know kind of got like a douchey face
I carry myself like in a way that
probably yeah absolutely no it's totally
fine it's actually really like to find
this you're a beautiful man but
um it's a very funny to watch the
preconceived notion or the small little
interaction
and uh how the temperaments changed and
it's like oh you're just like a little
goofball it's like a little weirdo
they're suddenly disarmed when they're
like Jesus is this guy gonna throw me or
something yeah and then I'll inherently
act overly childish especially
um when I've got clients I'm a trainer
uh I've got clients that are like uh
middle-aged to 25 women just because
it's like
like I'm safe like I'm uh totally I'm
just like just like your your kid's best
friend you know yeah but it's a it's
interesting the difference between the
reality of how anyone is and uh your
perception of that and how that like
will affect your
personal Behavior decision being like
meta aware of that yeah yeah I I could
say I think uh me like being covered in
tattoos since like a fairly young age
I've kind of experienced that like I
think it's unexpected sometimes when I'm
like kind of like a pretty pretty nice
sweet cheery cheery person a lot of the
times to strangers
um but it's it's not I love I love that
it's it's that same moment I love
watching that like oh yeah like oh if
you just leave room for this person to
be who they are in this moment you could
you could see them for who they really
are and who you really are you know get
your preconceived ideas out of the way
and just just be with the person and you
can experience
um I mean who they really are right now
yeah I mean and I'm sure this is
actually a pain point for many other
people like the being perceived not how
you are but I've always found it to be
lovely
lovely that little moment's so fun you
could just like see it happen and just
like there's something fun about
defining expectations and like a very uh
real way that's like uh handed and nice
that I I love it is that part of our um
I know like my personal like an infj
that's like an i i there's something
about me that likes being a mystery
there's something that's like I I know
that that's enticing like being a social
mystery like people not being able to
put their finger on like who I am and
what I'm about sometimes is there do you
have any of that with your personality
type I forget
um I think that I just like to be seen
as a I guess unique is such an annoying
word I'm language is failing to come to
me that encapsulates uh why I enjoy it
but I just
think I like this I just like subverting
expectations and being a little chaotic
in general just
throwing people off guard in like a very
interesting but not intimidating way and
just boiling people down to more of how
they are and then we can have like a
really odd and fun and one-off
conversation and maybe there's like a
deeper understanding and I uh and I'm
sure some of it's for attention too you
know it's just like yeah it's somebody
like noticing anything about you or like
realizing you're not like a shallow
[__] how they would have thought is
like immediately gratifying and I could
never circumvent the fact that attention
feels good yeah but that's not really
the whole of it you know yeah yeah yeah
it's a it's a piece of the puzzle for
sure but it's it's really not like I I I
like I like breaking stuff I like
you know I you know I like wearing
wearing all you know the the the shirt
and tie but then you know you lift up
the socks and you got yellow socks on
like that you know those little things
just kind of like breaking the thing
down a little bit like yeah well I just
like proving that all of this is silly
in the first place right when we go to
Rave Zone where pasties and mess
t-shirts you know like just like the
most because I like look really
traditionally masculine most the time
and just like the most eccentric and
oddly homoerotic clothing just to like
throw it off you know and I don't have
any uh traditionally gay mannerisms and
I'm I'm not gay so it's always just like
it's just fun to play with it because
it's just like a social construct I
don't know it's fun to subvert
expectations I guess this is what I'll
end it with you know yeah no I'm I'm
completely with you I understand
entirely I think it's part of uh as part
of what fuels fuels of us yeah exactly I
will still
puts on puts on denim vest uh under
eyeliner
I haven't worn eyeliner in years
um all right cool man well that was
excellent sir yeah yeah I appreciate
your time as always man thank you very
much I love that when we can make it
happen it's I know it's harder and
harder you know I mean living far away
but if there's ever a world where we
could figure out you know like we had
mentioned some sort of
continuous thing with the two of us I
feel like we
conversations so now so with school I
was realistically working 35 hours a
week going to school for 30 hours a week
I was getting home I was waking up at
like five getting home at eight so now I
only work 30 hours a week so I'm just
totally unencumbered I live like a
normal life so usually if you can make
it happen I could probably make it
happen too
well keep in mind I'll keep I'll keep
chugging along you know how I am about
this about the podcast I have my I have
my ups and downs with it but um I'm very
much enjoying it now I wanted to do a um
I've contemplated doing I might edit
this part out but uh like a live podcast
while I'm in town early July
and uh yeah that's what he said I don't
know if you'd be willing to to do it I
was going to ask you first but you and I
discuss
um and we have an uh I mean the audience
is going to be 10 people Max I feel like
not very many people hanging out with
our friends yeah but just hanging out
have a couple we'll record an episode
for an hour and then if there's any like
cool Concepts that come up and we'll
just discuss it and I just thought it
would be something cool to release as
like my 100th episode or something so I
don't know would be
comfortable with that I think it's going
to be different that'll be interesting
to do yeah I would happily do it yeah I
feel there's okay I know that this is
technically going to be listened to by a
non-zero amount of people and that's
fine there's something that feels so
much more intimate and like um
vulnerable about doing it in front of
people you know people that you probably
know right into something that's like uh
uniquely even though it's not uh
pretentious like although just
implicitly by coming on here I am
stating that my what I'm saying is worth
being heard and you should listen to it
going in front of actual humans is like
really saying that like I'm what I have
to say is so important that you should
show up to this physical place and
listen to me and talk about it
yeah yeah I uh dude I'm it's it's the
part of imposters it's a part of anybody
doing anything like if you have
something to say just [__] do it but
I because so I actually
um uh like a month ago I DJ for my first
time in Austin haven't I haven't played
out here but I didn't want to stand up
bro like I didn't I was like I kept what
I was practicing and I was planning out
like what I was going to bring I was
like I'm I'm not going to stand up for
this DJ set because I got I got it in my
head I was like I don't really feel like
I like I don't really want people like
staring at me I don't really want to be
like I'm the DJ up here and you guys bow
down to me there was something about it
I don't know if this is inherently
connected but I so I did my whole set
sitting down actually and you really did
it sitting I 100 did it sitting because
I got into my head about like just kind
of hiding like yeah like don't and I was
also like singing and stuff a lot too
like this was one of the first sets
where I I did like an eight or nine
original songs but um but it wasn't like
a I wanted to make sure it wasn't a look
at me sort of thing which I'm sure it
was I don't know it's it's something I'm
always toying with it but um
I don't know I think I'm gonna I'm DJing
tomorrow um at the same location I'm
gonna stand up tomorrow I think so we'll
send this progress baby yeah but I I I
do I I kind of like the image of I'm
over here in the corn like we're all
hanging out here and like I'm no better
than you I know
but I'm I just happen to be the one
who's running the music over here like
that's all like you guys oh cool you're
chilling you're drinking your beer cool
like keep drinking your beer like I'll
just control the music you just do your
thing I like that you know I don't want
this like we're coming to see Jacob from
the internet and like they're staring at
me and every single time I make a
transition they're like just staring at
my board of my fingers it's just I don't
know I
let's just let's just exist and I'll
just do what I'm good at over here and
you do what you're good at
you know that's interesting contention
yeah I don't know how I feel about it
well all right buddy I appreciate you
much
um yeah you can edit this out or
whatever yeah I'll probably edit out
this last this last minute yeah I
actually thought I felt really good
about that yeah yeah I think that one
went well yeah I'm glad that you brought
up um like like huntology and stuff and
Mark Fisher I think that's a really cool
thing and I think we could definitely
revisit it because I think it's yeah
it's very on the tongue it's very uh no
I'm Italian it's very um it's very right
now
you know what is the word looking
uh prudent
very relevant yeah I mean pretty much
everybody every name that I said is all
worthy of a long form explanation it
just felt bubble one I probably don't
know enough about it off the top off the
cuff to actually do that
and then uh
it just felt prudent to like elaborate
where hey look where the [__] is all
this coming from because like getting
the end of the thought chain is almost
impossible
um
I don't know hopefully it wasn't that
clumsy and at least it's hard to unknow
if somebody else is going to understand
what you're saying because I already
understand all the stuff you know so
it's like I don't know what needs to be
said all the way to explain this
yeah like you already got all the stuff
in the bag they might not even but I
think that's the thing about our
conversations that's the thing about any
sort of like philosophical conversations
is a lot of times you're not listening
to solve like it really is just a
listening practice of allowing the ideas
like
um like
you're kind of allowing what the person
is saying to like spark whatever like
you're not really necessarily trying to
argue with it or trying to fight
justification it's kind of like a let's
listen to something new and allow it to
do what it's doing to me so you don't
have to have that much backlog of it
yeah I listen to lectures of people that
actually do what they're talking about
like seven times you know
like even if it's just in the background
just like I this needs to get in here
mostly so let's just listen to the noise
well with with velocity inherently like
uh Victor Frankel's man search for
meaning I was rereading this morning and
it sounded like a new book and I'm
pretty positive I've read it before I've
listened to it before but I wasn't
sitting there listening to it like I was
probably like painting and like taking
notes and like allowing myself to think
about the philosophies I know that
relate to it or whatever you know and so
it's you don't always absorb it like
that's that's the beauty of it it's kind
of the same thing for like spiritual or
religious texts it's not meant to be
like oh I read it once and now I know
all the information it's like at
different times in your life with
different information and different
moods it kind of like Sparks different
things within you so that's it's funny
to say that because it's just it that is
very real but it's pretty it's
irrelevant to me currently it's um
I like the Matrix as a kid I watched it
again before I engaged with these two
thinkers John billiard and Mark Mark
Fisher and then I said out loud like wow
this is way less deep than I thought it
was like this is actually kind of though
if we look at the simulation bro so
[__] deep but I'm actually was just
an idiot and I didn't know what I didn't
know yet and then it became a deep again
when I understood the actual contextual
meaning of the thing and it was very
humbling in a way it's like you're
actually a [__] idiot all the time
maybe you should stop complaining about
stuff
oh I love it [__] you know
consistently unwinding what we thought
we knew yeah it's just I don't know you
did get sat down all the time which I
actually like it I think that's a really
good experience to have it was just it
was funny because it's like to somebody
somewhere if I said this to them and
they already knew I'm the [__] idiot
and you know what nice that's cool I
definitely was I'm okay with being the
idiot I don't care absolutely I'm happy
to be the idiot
okay all right brother well I appreciate
you man
um yeah feel free to uh any ideas you
have about the world any thoughts that
you have shoot me with a text give me a
call Snapchat me whatever like I'm I'll
get back to you whatever same thing
we've been doing
definitely really go to unload today
this felt pretty good because it's like
hard to talk to other people about this
because it's like gonna be like a I try
to I'll tell my girlfriend and she'll
just [__] listen she will she'll
listen to me no matter what
but it's like I feel really time
constrained to explain something that is
not worthy of constraints so I'm like
yeah well yeah write my paper about this
thing and there's this guy and he's like
this is what he believes kind of it's
important because you know this part of
this is like yeah here's how economics
works and you know it's like just too
many things I I seem to be um especially
with you and I I seem to be someone who
is pretty good at
understanding overall meaning like I'm
not like I'm not too literal of a person
I live in abstracts yeah and um uh
symbols and uh analogies that's how I
actually watch films and engage with art
it's nothing is ever literal I cannot
take things at face value just not how I
operate how do people watch movies and
just like focus on not the theme like
because people are not trained to one
kind of dumb to that's fine and it's not
because it's their fault they just
weren't educated to do that but I've
just always thought in abstracts so
that's why I've been really into media
criticism lately not to criticism in a
bad way but as in being critical of
films to suss out analysis because it's
like there's like a basic story here but
this is communicating a bunch of [__]
that maybe the authors didn't even know
and all I got to do is look at it with
the right lens to figure it out yeah
yeah I mean I think that's like like the
hero's journey is so fascinating in that
sense of like what's the underlining of
like every movie we we've ever watched
like in in the modern you know like like
Christian post-christianity world we
live in is it's the hero story you know
and that's
yeah a lot of people just don't ever see
themes so yeah I think that's why we why
we get along so well in a lot of ways
look at that well I turned my uh I don't
think I'm sweating
but that's uh when I went to Germany I
looked at like we went to [__] load of
museums and because of school I actually
am technically trained to analyze art
and it's just as I found that if you
live in abstractions everything is more
enriching you can get something out of
everything every meaningless symbol like
oh this building is like a really acute
square with really basic Windows okay so
this is brutalist architecture here's
the market pressure that made this
happen here oh here are the little
nuances how this is different from its
predecessors right so it's just like
this is a symbol that's communicating
something to me about Society or it
could just be a [__] building right
one of these things is infinitely more
interesting and a more fun way to look
at the world and one is boring and lame
yeah yeah one I can't do anything with
the literal sense of things a lot of the
times in the literal sense is again on
falsivity it's like
it's it's real if we're assuming the
story of like this whole thing is real
yeah [__] we just [__] talked about
that in a bunch of Senses yeah it's like
if you just take the [__] goggles
that you have and you look at the thing
it's like yeah that's the thing but it's
like is it really the [__] thing I
don't know take the glasses off it's
like 12 things yeah yeah yeah it is
actually at what level we we perceive
things it's I mean it kind of brings it
back to like the concept of time again
too
like I think we can
I I think that people like you and I
likely perceive time itself differently
than
um like a literal a literal thinker
and that's that's the whole thing we
come back at another date but yeah we
should talk about so actually a big part
of Mark Fisher's thing is temporality
being ruined because art won't make new
stuff
so like that's why Everything feels like
oh the 80s are back all the 70s are back
we've lost our transition in time and we
have a sense of
um retrograde amnesia where we can
remember everything up to a certain date
and then nothing Beyond it we just are
forced to relive the same four Decades
of culture over and over and over again
so everything plays on Nostalgia have
you have you looked much into outside of
like scoffing because it's kind of silly
like woo-woo um like the uh mandala
effect have you have you looked in or
heard anything about this
where it's like people will all
misremember the same thing like The
Bernstein Bears yeah but it keeps
getting weirder and [__] weirder and
I think that's probably because I'm
clicking on things on the internet and
so it's showing me the weird or like
more you know closer to the closer to
meeting Q himself of Q Anon sort of
clicks that I'm taking but um there is
something about that too that is is very
weird I think that like we're gonna
start misremembering things in like a
very chaotic way well that makes sense
though because everything's becoming a
like a shitty symbol of itself and
nothing is ever it's a real form anymore
so it's like
or misremembering the simulation of the
thing
that makes sense
yeah because you can't find bases like
once you misremember you can't like go
back to solidarity if solidarity was
never true it's just [__] everything
is [__] and that's like the
temporalness of reality art and culture
is just like suspended in time and
[__] a mess
because we just keep saying the same
symbols that are just like slightly
adjusted over and over and over again
until they just are self-referential and
meaningless and now it's just like a
[__] mess there's just like nothing
means anything and it's all
not how it should be I guess I think we
are going to upgrade like our our senses
or like dude I think something is gonna
[__] maybe it's through technology
maybe it's like the
I don't know it does it feel like to you
that we're getting to a heading of sorts
like something that's going to happen
like whether that's like you know the
[__] end of humans as we know it or
if it's like oh we discovered this new
particle and we can do things with it
and now I don't know it seems like well
I don't actually I don't think so it has
to I think it feels like we're
approaching something but we just keep
repeating the same Loop over and over
again and every time science gets a
little better more efficient they could
actually help people it never does it
always goes to making bombs or whatever
and uh it's just like a really boring
dystopian view what if science isn't the
way up
well I actually think that ideology is
the way out that's kind of why I said
that um
if I can get you to look at your own
ideology that's the best thing I could
ever do because the only way that we can
take all that science and make it good
is if we change the lens in which we
look at everything
maybe it's not the science itself it's
the application of it it's oh we found
out that we can do Quantum Computing but
we're not going to apply it correctly
because our ideology that we're bathed
in is not going to allow us to make
anyone's lives better or make anything
new
because we have a very rigid view of
what is true and what is real
but I wonder if there's a way that we
could take the the technology like the
inventions like the things that we were
doing for this certain thing and then
once we suddenly realized oh okay this
is not going to actually solve the
problems that we've been like hoping it
would we just suddenly take that
technology that you know magic and just
completely apply it to something that we
never thought of applying it to before
yeah I think that's a really like one
idea and fun yeah no it actually is
though and it honestly it makes sense
why it would it would happen because it
feels really good it's like oh [__] yes
someone's gonna save it somebody can't
do this thing everything's solved
but it almost feels like a red herring
for the real solution to things you know
where it's like what are the problems
we're having really bad material
conditions for most people most of the
world lives in abject poverty and is
subject to terrible working conditions
because of the machine of the market
that we've Chosen and uh housing costs a
lot and rich people are too rich
compared to poor people okay so these
all have really simple and mundane
answers which is like change at the base
change the economic system it's not sexy
we don't need science for it
but
people in charge will sell you what's
called retrofuturism they will take this
is a hauntological concept too they will
take the Sci-Fi tropes of the mid-80s
package them into new products and say
that they are revolutionary and they
they are going to help and change
because that Tony don't guess Bitcoin
I'll send you a video it's like two
hours you should watch it I really like
it okay but
there is like because of the stories and
the ideology that we have there is like
a very god-like savior complex that is
ingrained in Christianity
that's like the hero is a part of
western ideology and culture
so having somebody that will take all of
the symbols and all of the uh Concepts
from the ideas of sci-fi to save the
world all the media because we really uh
view the world through stories in a lot
of ways and media is really anchoring
they will give you like this Tesla truck
or like going to Mars and this is a red
herring from solving the real problem
which would fundamentally make them lose
power in society so it's like a two-fold
thing like their pacifying society and
gaining social
credit
or retrofitious ideas when actually all
the ideas that would help everybody is
stuff they actively don't want to happen
yeah part of me thinks like there's no
way we could get duped again but
you know here we are all the time baby
I'm getting duper right now guarantee it
I don't even know it I'm always getting
not even real dude
but maybe that's just maybe I'm just a
soy boy
beta liberal cook maybe science will
save everything I don't know maybe I
just need to like
I don't know eat beef
I think yeah that that is your problem
actually
um but Germanic and invade the Romans
really yeah I am
I don't know man
it's been fun though I enjoy your
company
it was damn good to see you man I feel
like it's been too long I know it has
been I know I feel like we didn't we
didn't like
um there's always so many things that
like I don't talk to very many people so
like there's so many things that I'm
like I want to tell Spencer I did want
to um I don't like want to get too deep
into it now we could say it for another
time but I want to talk to you about
like all this Kundalini stuff at some
point
like I generally like the way my belief
system is right now is so weird and it's
just been it's been like
Kundalini like isn't that a form of yoga
divine feminine energy yeah it's it's
essentially like there is
um energy coiled at the base of the
spine for all humans and it can be
awakened purposely or accidentally
although they say there's no accidents
if it's awakened even by you like going
to some breath work class and it like it
happens to you then that was divine
whatever but essentially I believe that
I have awoken something that I did not
know existed through all of my like I'm
Jake and I'm gonna kill myself if I
don't figure out what the hell's wrong
going on with my brain and I was doing
all this breath work and yoga and
meditation and smoking a lot of weed and
blah blah blah
um I basically awaken something within
myself that um
like it is very uh psychologically
psychologically destabilizing in a lot
of ways but I think that I've like sat
with it enough that um I kind of
understand it and doesn't make me like
so crazy I have a very annoying and
materialist view of this stuff that's
probably pretty deflating but well I do
think that the actual sensation is
[__] cool and if you no matter what
it comes from whatever you think it
comes from trying to get there is tight
yeah so there's there's so many people
you can listen to that uh like their
experience of it is literally like
um like I just listened to somebody on
an interview yesterday or something that
theirs was they had done a meditation
class or like it was something it was a
couple days afterwards and they woke up
in the middle of the night to the only
way they can describe it was the feeling
of energy shooting out of the top of
their head and then they just like sat
there staring at the wall for 20 minutes
like and then you know it's a different
kind of like weird sort of things start
happening in their life but um there's
like tons of people where they have the
actual moment of like
and then some people are basically in
like a some level of Enlightenment for
like some period of time like months
weeks um like Eckhart Tolle for example
like when he had his near-death
experience he sat on a bench for [__]
two years and just like tried to like
stabilize it's basically like your your
perception of reality is so different
afterwards but like you don't really
have the old comparison of how reality
was to like compare it to so you're not
really understanding what you're what
you're fully feeling and so you're
basically on a psychedelic trying to get
used to how the Psychedelic feels and
like this is now reality and so a lot of
ways like I had um a changing of my
Consciousness it's like a changing of my
perception of reality rather and I had
to like
understand it and
um
I don't know in in a lot of it kind of
points a lot of my understanding not
that it's like capital T truth but
pointing towards things that kind of
feel right it's a lot of the Kundalini
stuff like I have this book on it um
that's like it's completely based in
science but like it's so hard to connect
any of it with science even if I'm
reading like studies it almost ruins it
almost ruins it yeah I'm thinking that
the scientific way if if I just get it
explained to me in a scientific way then
I'll be able to make sense of it and I
can explain to other people it'll make
sense to me and it's like yeah it almost
ruins it it makes it more like I know
for a fact I want to take LSD it binds
to my um serotonin receptor two site and
it closes it off and it doesn't leave
for eight hours but it doesn't know but
the wall still [__] melts yeah okay
yeah I mean I don't actually know you
can't I know where it's going I know
words hooking up to I know that it's
safe I know it's fine for me but the
[__] walls melt and I can hear my
friends think okay
yeah so when you can find that on
science direct I don't really know I
remember saying at one point before I
like even kind of it was like years
before like the edge of my depression
where I like really started like looking
it up I just like had dealt with
depression I had friends with depression
I remember like dying on the hill I was
like so like you guys don't understand
depression is a chemical imbalance in
the brain the person cannot help I'm
like what how the [__] is that an answer
but okay what what is that what does
that even mean though like how is that
an answer it's like what are you even
saying like what fundamentally doesn't
change your material condition to
understand why it's happening right yeah
like oh I understand that I might not
produce enough serotonin for whatever
reason okay well I'm still [__] sad
though like yeah yeah but but what
caused these cause these chemical
reactions or the lack of chemicals and
like what were the actions of the person
leading up to it and what are their
genetics and what are you know there's
like all these tons of things that come
into it not like
you need to just like completely listen
to the person who's depressed just
because they have a chemical imbalance
it's just I don't know I come to terms
with it in and out
yeah that's great I don't know well it's
like it kind of sucks The Human
Experience is kind of shitty because
it's just like an evolutionary process
and there's nothing that is evolutionary
advantageous about not being depressed
like your biology doesn't care it
doesn't doesn't increase survival at all
really so it's like like you can still
make kids so I mean well even socially
it actually brings you down the social
hierarchy like there is there is an
innate yuckiness that comes with
depression or anxiety or like uh
um anxiety was a great adaptation
because like oh there's Tigers oh man I
continue to be anxious about that but
identifying identifying as being someone
who is anxious and like allowing them to
be a personality belonging to that to be
the thing that you make podcast episodes
about is inherently ucky to the outside
world yeah like there's not females who
are
you know running for the protection of
the dude who's anxious it's just it's a
different thing it's uh it changes
things it's different so for that
anxiety gets you to kill [__] Tigers
bro
yeah yeah sure yeah I guess I'm talking
about anxiety versus
um like the identity of being anxious I
I am here with anxiety that gets in the
way of
discussing anxiety oh man I'm so sorry I
try to cut I'm trying to cut that out it
seems that the uh the compressor did its
jobs job and so it was just hit me I was
like oh man that's loud I hope my levels
were okay I try to keep this at the same
distance from my mouth but not too far
away or closer I think they're good and
I I do everything in post anyway like so
I record this within Zoom but then I
also like I have Ableton running in the
background recording my audio on this
end just so my voice can sound that much
better but it just gives me literally
way more extra work for no [__]
reason so I should just record it all in
zoom and post it as it is
sometimes I feel that I advertise myself
as an audio engineer so I need to not
have a podcast that sounds shitty but
then I make music that's like inherently
a Lo-Fi style that sounds like recorded
through a butthole you just like
purposely compressed the [__] out of it
I do a lot of weird things that I do
like for artistic yes it's artistic but
also it's like well it's going to take
me another two hours if I do it the
other way this sounds bad because of art
all right [__] leave me alone yeah
thanks Lo-Fi you really led the way like
this is giving me that Nostalgia feel to
it
yeah all right cool brother well um I
think I mean we always say this but I
think we should just uh hop on a phone
call as often as we can just super down
I'm finally not uncumbered enough I was
dude I was so over encumbered for like
two years just with school too that it's
so liberating
so I'd be super down to do that well I'm
available fairly often a lot of times
um I'm I'm at home like I'm kind of in
an ethereal realm of just creating or
just being stoned in my apartment so
that's where I'm at a lot of times so
call whenever but um I I just started
with another company doing stagehand
stuff so hopefully my schedule isn't
like super open but um oh and I'm
working at the dock a lot too that's a
[__] banging job it's a cool job man
it's uh it's funny because it's actually
kind of difficult like um not difficult
like mentally difficult for me like I
just I'm just not the same social guy I
used to be
um not not just that it's draining but
like even just you know put 25 year old
me on a boat with like 12 you know cute
bachelorette girls and I'm just gonna be
a flirt and make sure they have a good
time whatever and now I'm like I kind of
just want to sit here and like not
really talk to any of you like so it's
yeah I've found a very weird autism
creep into my own life where it's like
I'm serious like this fundamental the
way that I'm thinking all the time is
just like not appropriate for reality or
anybody else you're going to talk to or
it's almost like [__] jarring when
somebody's like hey how are you I'm like
oh my God fine I think I get I don't
really think about it you're like you're
gonna find me a [__] football right
now like uh
that ain't it so sometimes I'll lit like
sometimes almost all the time I'll drive
to work or I'm driving to somewhere and
like when I take my keys out of the
ignition the philosophy conversation
that that was just listening or like the
the guided meditation about the illusory
self just shuts off and then I get out
of the car and then I'm having like a
regular ass conversation with a person
weather's nice I guess yeah it's uh yeah
so but but it's fun though it's good uh
it's very much
um this sounds like one of those like
toxic Millennial uh things I'm bringing
in but it is very much like oh I need to
be social I know it's good for me I know
that it helps me to like meet new people
and kind of no it is good it is good
yeah it is I do miss it a lot I see
people working out together all the time
like younger kids like a gag of them I'm
like dude that looks [__] awesome
just hanging out
but now it's like being boys dudes being
Bros you know yeah but now you're like I
gotta not waste my time in the gym and I
I've got to get shoulders and buys done
today and yeah I never say anything to
him like I came here for a reason
I have enough friends yeah you're like
I'm a serious weightlifter you guys
aren't serious yeah kinda
yeah all right brother well um lunch
appreciate you man yeah what lunch it is
I'll be in touch soon man I'll probably
yeah I still have a backlog of episodes
to post but I'll probably post this one
sooner than those just because I like
posting more recent ones so I'll let you
know
all right brother I'm gonna I'm gonna
end this thing have a good day my friend
you too much love
[Music]
conversations with ourselves
knowledge is power
[Music]
reality is